<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Positions - Volt Europa</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://www.volteuropa.org/vacancies</link>
    <item>
      <title>Merchandise Co-lead (female)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Volt Europa has resolved to have all its teams be lead by gender-balanced co-leads, and this is a vacancy for the &lt;strong&gt;female&lt;/strong&gt; position, as the male co-lead is currently filled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Key Facts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reporting to: Julia Pitterman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working closely with co-lead Angelos Arampatzis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Times:  15 hrs per week or more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: no particular location is required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no compensation for this voluntary position&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deadline for sending the applications: 12 January 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The position&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Merchandise team, as part of the Volt Europa Sustainable Financing team, supports the Volt Europa Treasurer in working towards financial sustainability with the sale of high-quality and creative Volt Europa merchandise. This merchandise produced not only ensures financial growth yet also increases Volt Europa visibility and branding as products are used at campaigns and events.&lt;br&gt;The Merchandise co-lead is responsible for managing the sale of Volt-branded products and further developing our current platform to ensure national chapters can buy the needed material, while seeking to constantly improve quality and profits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tasks and Competencies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Overseeing key merchandise activities such as sale campaign preparation, ensuring KPIs are met and coordinating with national representatives (80% of time spent)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Proposing new and creative strategies to resolve product or finance-related issues concerning merchandise (10% of time spent)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Leading team members and empowering other members in the Sustainable Financing team (10% of time spent)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Must have skills:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Digital savvy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attention to detail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Website development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stakeholder management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creativity, analytical thinking, digital design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborative, team orientated approach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optional: Experience in digital design and merchandise sales. Experience in managing teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;We offer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading the Merchandise team means supporting the leadership to achieve financial sustainability while ensuring we provide our community with needed Volt-branded products. Being part of the Sustainable Financing team will ensure that each individual also gain key knowledge on non-profit management while working with individuals from all over Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Application&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send an email to julia.pitterman@volteuropa.org with your CV, motivation letter (maximum one page) and a video where you introduce yourself and tell what you would like to achieve in this role.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 17:24:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>David Arnemann</author>
      <link>http://www.volteuropa.org/merchandise_co_lead</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Events Co-lead (female)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Volt Europa has resolved to have all its teams be lead by gender-balanced co-leads, and this is a vacancy for the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;female&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; position as the male position is filled.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Key Facts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reporting to: Eileen O’Sullivan &amp;amp; Reinier van Lanschot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working closely with co-lead Michael Vogtmann&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hours:  10-20 hrs per week (depending on time of year and events to be planned)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: no particular location is required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no compensation for this voluntary position&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deadline for sending the applications: 12 January 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The position&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the Events co-lead is to have an overview of all European events and actions &lt;br&gt;Happening. Sharing the capacities needed specifically for larger, long-term events such as the GA and the Volt Festival. Creating a pan-European Team spirit // External: Bringing media attention to Volt; Strengthening the narrative of Volt Europa as a pan-European movement; Providing a stage to present Volt Europa’s policies; Supporting election campaigns, when possible (national, regional, local).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Key responsibilities &amp;amp; duties&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supervises and coordinates projects. Communicates projects with national Events Leads. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coordinating large scale European events such as the GA with all relevant members (e.g. the national Events lead) (65% of time spent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Informing national event leads on events and actions coming up but also receiving feedback and input (20% of time spent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coordinating with other teams (e.g. Design, Communications)(15% of time spent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Your experience and skills&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Languages: ideally multiple languages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High motivational level to work for the European Level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organisational talent, maintaining structures, practical thinking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Must: Ability to communicate and keep everyone up to date&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideally experience in organizing events (i.e. local team or national Event Lead with 6 months experience)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Open for adventures, because this whole thing is one” (says co-lead Michael) and able to maintain humour in stressful times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Must have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;High Organisational skills, &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;maintaining structures and communicating, &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;coordinating multiple teams &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Team oriented approach &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Communication skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Problem solving aptitude&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Leadership skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Good organisational skills and attention to detail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;A spirit of entrepreneurship and initiative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optional: Project management experience, Volt experience, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Application&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send an email to &lt;a href="mailto:toeileen.osullivan@volteuropa.org"&gt;eileen.osullivan@volteuropa.org&lt;/a&gt; and reinier.van.lanschot@volteuropa.org with your CV, motivation letter (maximum one page) and a video where you introduce yourself and tell what you would like to achieve in this role.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 17:18:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>David Arnemann</author>
      <link>http://www.volteuropa.org/events_co_lead</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Analytics Co-lead</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are looking for a male and a female co-lead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Key Facts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reporting to: Valerie Sternberg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hours: 10 hrs per week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: no particular location is required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no compensation for this voluntary position&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deadline for sending the applications: 12 January 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The position&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EUR Data Analytics team is at the core of the efforts of Volt being an evidence-based organization. It utilizes the methodological skills of its members to conduct empirical studies, and creates analytical pipelines to enhance the capability of Volt to shape the political discourse in Europe. The Co-Leads of the EUR Data Analytics team will oversee and coordinate the activities of their team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Key responsibilities &amp;amp; duties&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The activities of the EUR Data Analytics team range from such diverse topics as social media analyses over the design of statistical tools for the prediction of Volt’s electoral success to the analyses of Volt’s member-base and Volt’s internal communications. The team coordinates and aligns on these activities with the national D&amp;amp;A teams. The work of the EUR Data Analytics team involves a diverse set of stakeholders from the local level to the European level, as well as cooperating closely with various functional teams (especially comms and tech). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our current workstreams are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Internal Data (Analysis of Workplace and the volt.team membership database),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Social Media Data (Analysis of our Social Media Activities, Facebook + Instagram)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Open Public Data (Election Analysis, Socio-economic data)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Survey Team (Creating and distributing surveys to the Volt membership, as well as to external populations)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tasks and Competencies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coordinates the overall organization and output of the team (10% of time)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aligns on activities and needs with national teams (10% of time spent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develops new and improves established workstreams together with the team members, (30% of time)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organises and moderates team calls (currently two weekly calls) (10% of time)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acts as a link to key stakeholders such as other functional teams, national boards, or the EUR board (20% of time)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strategises on the development of the team together with the EUR leadership (10% of time)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trains the EUR Data Analytics team (10% of time)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Must have:&lt;br&gt;- Project management, Organizational skills&lt;br&gt;- Communication skills, fluent English&lt;br&gt;- Experience in conducting empirical research&lt;br&gt;- Analytical mindset&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optional: Experience in teaching&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Application&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send an email to &lt;a href="mailto:valerie.sternberg@volteuropa.org"&gt;valerie.sternberg@volteuropa.org&lt;/a&gt; with your CV, motivation letter (maximum one page) and a video where you introduce yourself and tell what you would like to achieve in this role.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 17:10:40 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>David Arnemann</author>
      <link>http://www.volteuropa.org/data_analytics_co_lead</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legal Co-lead</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are looking for a male and a female co-lead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Key Facts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reporting to: Sofia Gentiloni Silveri &amp;amp; Valerie Sternberg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hours:  10/15 hrs per week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: no particular location is required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no compensation for this voluntary position&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deadline for sending the applications: 12 January 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The position&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You manage Volt Europa’s legal issues and create synergies between the work of the different national legal teams, provide ad hoc legal support to national chapters without legal team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Key responsibilities &amp;amp; duties&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provide legal advice and assistance to the Board, to the VCR and to the other functional teams, in various matters related to the activity of Volt Europa. Ability to coordinate the work of national legal teams, to provide assistance and to create synergies and opportunities of knowledge and best practice sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide legal documents and legal advice &amp;amp; assistance (e.g. code of conduct, statutes, regulations, contractual documents, assets…), working closely together with other functional teams and dedicated teams, such as the Governance Commission (65% of time spent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage the EUR Team and Co-ordinate the national teams  (10% of time spent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Miscellaneous admin duties and support financial/tech teams  (20% of time spent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data entry  (5% of time spent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Must have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Good legal training and attention to detail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Analysis of various legislation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Sensitivity to the diverse legal European environment - comparative approach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Communication skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Problem solving aptitude&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Leadership skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Team oriented approach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Good organisational skills and attention to detail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optional: Basic Excel database skill, Academic qualifications, Qualified lawyer in a Member State, a plus, Work experience and skills, Similar previous experience, Knowledge of French, and other languages, a plus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Application&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send an email to &lt;a href="mailto:valerie.sternberg@volteuropa.org"&gt;valerie.sternberg@volteuropa.org&lt;/a&gt; and sofia.gentiloni@volteuropa.org with your CV, motivation letter (maximum one page) and a video where you introduce yourself and tell what you would like to achieve in this role.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 17:06:55 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>David Arnemann</author>
      <link>http://www.volteuropa.org/legal_co_lead</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HR Co-lead (male)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Volt Europa has resolved to have all its teams be lead by gender-balanced co-leads, and this is a vacancy for the &lt;strong&gt;male&lt;/strong&gt; position, as the female co-lead position is currently filled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Key Facts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reporting to: Cornelia German &amp;amp; Reinier van Lanschot &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working closely with current co-lead Anna Gvelesiani&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hours:  8-10 hrs per week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: no particular location is required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no compensation for this voluntary position&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The position&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key purpose of the EUR HR team is to take care of the workforce management inside the organization. HR puts in place and oversees procedures for new and existing members to facilitate them getting on board and finding their role. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Key responsibilities &amp;amp; duties&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coordination between the European and national HR level and organization of an efficient information- and workflow, create and implement HR-procedures. Ability to coordinate and distribute the tasks among the team, coordinate the standardization of HR procedures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Creation, documentation and standardization of HR procedures. (35% of time spent)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Manage the EUR Team and Co-ordinate the national teams (35% of time spent)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Miscellaneous admin duties, assistance via email (30% of time spent)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Must have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Communication skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Problem solving aptitude&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Leadership skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Team oriented approach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Good organisational skills &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Basic excel database skills &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Understanding of organisational complexity and structure on micro- and macro level &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Motivational and diplomatic skills &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optional: Administration skills, English language skills, similar previous experience, practical thinking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Application&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send an email to and cornelia.german@volteuropa.org and &lt;a href="mailto:reinier.van.lanschot@volteuropa.org"&gt;reinier.van.lanschot@volteuropa.org&lt;/a&gt; with your CV, motivation letter (maximum one page) and a video where you introduce yourself and tell what you would like to achieve in this role.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 17:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>David Arnemann</author>
      <link>http://www.volteuropa.org/hr_co_lead</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General Secretary Co-Lead</title>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Key Facts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reporting to:&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; Volt Europa Board &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time required:&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; &amp;gt;25 h/week&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location:&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; No fixed location necessary, but Brussels Utrecht or Berlin is practical.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;There is no compensation for this voluntary position&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The position&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;The key responsibility of the General Secretary is to take ownership of key organisational and administrative activities that ensure Volt Europa can function effectively to create the impact it seeks to create.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Responsibilities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stakeholder management (Time spent:&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; 50%)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;The EUR board&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;
&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;European functional teams &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;(campaign, support, policy, external relations) &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;The national boards  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;National General Secretaries &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;and operating as a key contact between the levels above and below as well as prioritizing workloads.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working closely with the legal team (Time spent:&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; 25%)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;To ensure that the organization fulfills the legal requirements&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Working on legal membership structure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Manage and approve legal membership in EUR level&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Working on the structure of the organization and its improvement&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ensuring key processes are in place to professionalise (Time Spent: &lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;25%)&lt;/span&gt;, such as&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Implementing new procedures and organizational/administrative systems&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Managing databases and other IT tools in cooperation with Tech Team &amp;amp; DPO&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Bringing teams together and kick off key projects and TF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Working on documentation as contracts, NDAs, agendas, minutes, draft proposals, emails&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Working on KM with internal/external experts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We seek the following essential qualifications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Leadership &amp;amp; long term planning skills&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Project management knowledge&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Good communication and building-relationship skills&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Good organisational skills and attention to detail&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Ability to take responsible decisions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Flexibility, organization and time management skills&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Ability to act immediately on urgent issues and high availability&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We welcome the following qualifications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Ability to use IT tools (databases, NB, GD etc.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Ability to be proactive and take initiatives when is needed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Ability to exchange best practices in a clear manner&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;EU Law basic knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Please send an email to &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:valerie.sternberg@volteuropa.org"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;valerie.sternberg@volteuropa.org&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:reinier.van.lanschot@volteuropa.org"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;reinier.van.lanschot@volteuropa.org&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; with your CV, motivation letter (maximum one page) and a video where you introduce yourself and tell what you would like to achieve as General Secretary. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 16:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>David Arnemann</author>
      <link>http://www.volteuropa.org/general_secretary_co_lead</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Audit Co-lead</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Volt Europa has resolved to have all its teams be lead by gender-balanced co-leads, and this is a vacancy for the male and the female position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Key Facts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reporting to: Julia Pitterman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time required: 15 hrs per week or more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: no particular location is required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no compensation for this voluntary position&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deadline for sending the applications: 12 January 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Position&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Audit team, as part of the Volt Europa Sustainable Financing team, provides independent assurance that Volt Europa’s risk management, governance and internal control processes are operating effectively. The team has a double mandate of ensuring Volt Europa AISBL’s is effectively and appropriately operating, whilst also providing support to national chapters in need of professional counsel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Audit co-leads deal with issues that are critical to the survival and prosperity of Volt Europa. They go beyond financial risks and statements, to consider wider issues such as reputational risks, growth and processes. They support the Board in making the organization succeed by reporting on how systems and processed designed to keep the organization on track are working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tasks and Competencies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Creating a Volt Europa audit methodology to effectively assess the management of risk and internal controls (60% of time spent)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Evaluating key documentation (e.g. financial statements) as well as processes in place at the European level to provide fit-for-purpose recommendations (30% of time spent)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Leading team members and empowering other members in the Sustainable Financing team  (10% of time spent)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical audit skills, knowledge on internal audit standards and codes of practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effective communication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project management, analytical skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attention to detail, creativity, analytical thinking, digital design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborative, team orientated approach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Professional experience (min. 2 years) in audit, preferably internal audit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience in managing teams (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;We offer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading the Audit team means supporting the leadership in removing possible risks in different areas, especially financial management. By doing so, the Audit co-leads will gain key knowledge on how Volt Europa is run at all levels and will take part in a unique opportunity to create the foundations for future audit functions – spearheading a critical and strategic apparatus. You will lead innovative and interesting projects while working with individuals from all over Europe that are committed to professionalizing Volt Europa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Application&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send an email to julia.pitterman@volteuropa.org with your CV, motivation letter (maximum one page) and a video where you introduce yourself and tell what you would like to achieve in this role.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 16:49:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>David Arnemann</author>
      <link>http://www.volteuropa.org/audit_co_lead</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finance Co-lead (female)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Volt Europa has resolved to have all its teams be lead by gender-balanced co-leads, and this is a vacancy for the &lt;strong&gt;female&lt;/strong&gt; position as the male position is filled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Key Facts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reporting to: Julia Pitterman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working closely with Christophe Quirynen (male co-lead)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time required:  15 hrs per week or more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: no particular location is required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no compensation for this voluntary position&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deadline for sending the applications: 12 January 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Position&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Finance team, as part of the Volt Europa Sustainable Financing team, supports the Volt Europa Treasurer in working towards financial sustainability while finding innovative solutions to complex problems. The Finance team is responsible for key accounting and reporting activities as well as strategic financial management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Finance co-leads are responsible for managing the preparation of key financial documentation such as financial statements, invoices, day-to-day record keeping as well as reporting. The Finance co-leads, as close advisors to the Volt Europa Treasurer, also have oversight of strategic financial planning and budgets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tasks and Competencies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Production of key financial documentation such as financial statements, day-to-day recording and invoices (70% of time spent)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Advise on strategic financial planning and budget projections (20% of time spent)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Leading team members and empowering other members in the Sustainable Financing team  (10% of time spent)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finance and accounting skills, great organizational skills, rigor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Budget planning, stakeholder management skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attention to detail, effective communication, collaborative, team orientated approach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Professional experience (min. 2 years) in accounting or financial services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience in managing teams (optional).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;We offer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading the Finance team means supporting the leadership to achieve financial sustainability while ensuring that we professionalize on all fronts. By supporting the Treasurer in strategic planning and budgets, the Finance co-lead is taking part in a unique experience of creating an innovative financial structure for Volt Europa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Finance co-lead will also learn key aspects of non-profit management while working with individuals from all over Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Application&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send an email to julia.pitterman@volteuropa.org with your CV, motivation letter (maximum one page) and a video where you introduce yourself and tell what you would like to achieve in this role.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 16:41:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>David Arnemann</author>
      <link>http://www.volteuropa.org/finance_co_lead</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expansion Co-lead</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are looking for a male and a female co-lead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Key Facts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reporting to: Reinier van Lanschot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time required:  8 hrs per week or more. Weekly expansion meetings and regular check of expansion related communications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: no particular location is required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no compensation for this voluntary position&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deadline for sending the applications: 12 January 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The position&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Expansion EU Lead focuses on expanding the Volt organization, its resources and presence. &lt;br&gt;The Lead inspires by connecting and motivating Volt members to create a united European community that constructively and strategically effectively and efficiently realizes growth for the Volt organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Key responsibilities &amp;amp; duties&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* Develop and implement expansion strategy for Europe&lt;br&gt;* Connect people and facilitate teams to encourage collaboration&lt;br&gt;* Moderate meetings to achieve effective outcomes&lt;br&gt;* Performing and delegating operational work to achieve strategic goals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tasks and Competencies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Liaise with  and help National Teams (50% of time spent)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Managing the expansion team (30% of time spent)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Creating and implementing our strategy for growth (20% of time spent)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Must have:&lt;br&gt;* Good social and communication skills&lt;br&gt;* Stimulating and supportive characteristics&lt;br&gt;* English language written and spoken on good level&lt;br&gt;* An entrepreneurial spirit&lt;br&gt;* Management and leadership skills&lt;br&gt;* Communication skills&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optional: A lot of experience in Volt is a plus. Experience in building teams, taking initiatives and exploring new territories as well. A strong European network too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Application&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send an email to reinier.van.lanschot@volteuropa.org with your CV, motivation letter (maximum one page) and a video where you introduce yourself and tell what you would like to achieve in this role.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 16:32:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>David Arnemann</author>
      <link>http://www.volteuropa.org/expansion_co_lead</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Communications Co-lead (male)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Volt Europa has resolved to have all its teams be lead by gender-balanced co-leads, and this is a vacancy for the &lt;strong&gt;male&lt;/strong&gt; position, as the female co-lead position is currently filled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Key Facts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reporting to: Reinier van Lanschot. Working closely with co-lead Daniela Ramos Giraldo. As well as the co-leads of the comms subteams and the accountable board members of those subteams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hours: &amp;gt;12 hrs per week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: no particular location is required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no compensation for this voluntary position&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time limit for sending the applications: 12 January 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Purpose of the position&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Communications team of Volt Europa is in charge of the Communications strategy, as well as the production of the external communications &lt;br&gt;of the party’s European level. The Comms Co-leads are in charge of coordinating the work of the team with regards to the party’s Social Media presence, graphics design and PR word and strengthening Volt’s brand, narrative and media presence whilst also coordinating messaging and content with national Communications teams. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Key responsibilities &amp;amp; duties&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Co-Leads will coordinate the Strategy, Design, PR and Social Media sub-teams to ensure overall communicative cohesion. The leads also coordinate with the national communications teams to ensure alignment between the different national chapters of Volt Europa. The co-leads also work on the overall strategic communications of Volt. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The leads also support in content creation, such as for example, but not limited to, drafting of press releases and social media statements on various social media platforms, and graphic design. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tasks and Competencies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Liaise with National Teams (40% of time spent)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; European Team Leadership (40% of time spent)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Content creation (20-50% (to decrease as team capacity is built))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Must have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Leadership and management skills&lt;br&gt;- Communication skills (messaging, framing and spinning) &lt;br&gt;- Time managing skills &lt;br&gt;- Multitasking capacity&lt;br&gt;- Good organisational skills&lt;br&gt;- Attention to detail&lt;br&gt;- Team orientated approach&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optional:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project management experience, Conflict resolution experience, writing skills, graphic design, Qualifications relating to communications and public relations is meriting. Experience working in the field of professional communications and communication within Volt is meriting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Application&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send an email to reinier.van.lanschot@volteuropa.org with your CV, motivation letter (maximum one page) and a video where you introduce yourself and tell what you would like to achieve in this role.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 14:11:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>David Arnemann</author>
      <link>http://www.volteuropa.org/communications_co_lead</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intranet Admin &amp; Helpdesk</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Volt movement is growing! So is our infrastructure and we need help supporting it. Members and those who want to be need our support with questions regarding our intranet and internal communication tools. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 23:47:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>David Arnemann</author>
      <link>http://www.volteuropa.org/intranet_admin_helpdesk</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backend Developer</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Help us build and improve our internal member and analytics platforms!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 23:47:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>David Arnemann</author>
      <link>http://www.volteuropa.org/backend_developer</link>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
