<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>NationBuilder Blog</title>
    <description>Learn what's new at NationBuilder, software for leaders.</description>
    <link>http://nationbuilder.com/blog</link>
    <item>
      <title>Diary of a candidate Vol.6: “Ready for the launch!”</title>
      <description>&lt;h3 style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;img title="diary-illustration-120" src="https://d3n8a8pro7vhmx.cloudfront.net/3dna/pages/47133/attachments/original/1576767840/Candidate-Jackie-days-120_2x-META.png?1576767840" alt="" width="568" height="316"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #2f96bf;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;a style="color: #2f96bf;" href="https://nationbuilder.com/journal_candidate_episode_6"&gt;Read this in &lt;span style="color: #2f96bf;"&gt;French&lt;/span&gt; 🇫🇷&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;We are Lison Laissus and Oliver Wells, NationBuilder Account Managers based in the London office. Having worked with many political parties and campaigns, we want to share what we’ve learned for people new to the process. This series is a step-by-step journey of a fictional candidate running for office, informed by our shared experience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 06:42:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Lison Laissus</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/diary_candidate_vol_6</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>November 23, 2019</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A year ago today, my friend Jim Gilliam drew his last breath.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It was a labored breath, through second-hand lungs that had extended his life for over a decade.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;He almost didn’t get them. So when he did, the only thing that mattered to him was making it worth it, paying back the debt he felt he owed to the people who had sacrificed so much to keep him alive. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 10:46:13 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Lea Endres</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/november_23_2019</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key strategies to accelerate your #GivingTuesday success</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;It’s about that time of year — #GivingTuesday is quickly approaching, so we want to make sure you have everything you need to raise money and meet your goals.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;We know there are a ton of different approaches to end-of-year fundraising, so here are some key strategies to accelerate your #GivingTuesday success.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 12:54:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Katie Angelo</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/key_strategies_to_accelerate_your_givingtuesday_success</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The first General Election post-GDPR: Key tips on using NationBuilder privacy tools</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;This December’s General Election will be the first in the UK since the much discussed General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) came to fruition in May 2018, giving individuals greater control over their personal data held by third-parties. GDPR doesn’t have to be an obstacle; instead it is an opportunity to build better relationships with supporters and potential voters. At NationBuilder, we have developed a suite of tools to help our European customers do just that. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;The idea of owning your own data has always been at the heart of what we at NationBuilder believe in. As a result, when the GDPR was introduced last year, we were well placed to serve hundreds of our European customers as they make the most of this opportunity. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a rel="noopener" href="https://nationbuilder.com/ten_key_gdpr_takeaways" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;We ran an event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; to discuss the opportunities offered from the regulations, developed a &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a rel="noopener" href="https://support.nationbuilder.com/en/articles/2362974-advanced-privacy-tools" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;suite of advanced privacy tools&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; to help customers not just remain compliant but to actively strengthen their supporter relationships, and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a rel="noopener" href="https://nationbuilder.com/tags/gdpr" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;shared best practice examples&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; on how these tools can be best used.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;This year’s UK General Election will once again see the GDPR in the spotlight, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a rel="noopener" href="https://ico.org.uk/about-the-ico/news-and-events/news-and-blogs/2019/11/information-commissioner-reminds-political-parties-they-must-comply-with-the-law-ahead-of-general-election/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;with the ICO writing to all major political parties&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; to remind them of the need to comply. Many commentators see the GDPR as a restriction, but we see it as an opportunity to build trust, confidence and relationships. As Elizabeth Denham, the Information Commissioner, put it:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;“I do not believe data protection is standing in the way of your success. It’s not privacy or innovation––it’s privacy and innovation.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Here are some of the ways that we’ve seen preparation for GDPR turned into an advantage and top tips for candidates, parties, charities, and advocacy groups ahead of the forthcoming General Election: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Capturing and tracking consents in one, central and dynamic place&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;: Having previously worked on political and charity campaigns, I’ve experienced first hand how arduous it can be when someone unsubscribes from communications from your organisation. I’ve had to go into multiple databases used by different functions of the campaign, plus mark opt-outs in various spreadsheets. Even then I couldn’t be sure that someone else wasn’t using an out of date spreadsheet that was exported from a database. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left: 30px;"&gt;With &lt;a rel="noopener" href="https://support.nationbuilder.com/en/articles/2363040-use-advanced-privacy-to-effectively-target-supporters" target="_blank"&gt;NationBuilder consents,&lt;/a&gt; when someone opts out it’s automatically logged in your database, meaning that there’s no manual work to mark people accordingly, given the website and database are integrated. It also means that any communication from broadcasters can immediately take these into account by &lt;a rel="noopener" href="https://nationbuilder.com/email_communication_after_gdpr" target="_blank"&gt;using saved filters directly and dynamically linked to these consents&lt;/a&gt;. Not only does this save a huge amount of administrative time but it also removes a significant headache from any compliance team as they are able to keep track of where the data is and audit log of consents, all in one central place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Use granular consents to develop relationships: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Key to the GDPR is giving citizens the option to control how they are communicated with. This is important for any movement—not just for remaining compliant but for building a relationship with supporters at a time when many organisations are competing for their attention. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a rel="noopener" href="https://nationbuilder.com/advanced_privacy_targeting" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;By collecting granular consent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; using NationBuilders tools, you can learn what supporters are interested in, how regularly they want to hear from you, and through what medium (email, text, call, whatsapp etc); this will go a long way to help you stand out from the crowd, ultimately, leading to more and better engagement, better delivery, and higher conversion rates in the long-term.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Get your messages into inboxes: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;In today's age, competing for space in your supporter’s email inbox is a crucial piece of getting your message through. In order to get there, email reputation is everything and email providers like Gmail, Yahoo and Hotmail look at previous behaviour from other users in relation to emails you’ve sent  to decide what is spam. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left: 30px;"&gt;Therefore, by using consents to target emails; supporters will expect your emails containing content that they are interested in, and thus be more likely to open and click their links. Previous historic engagement is the basis of your future email reputation. This means the more people that open and engage with your emails, the more likely those emails are to show up in the inboxes of other supporters.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Easily process ‘right of access’ requests&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a rel="noopener" href="https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-data-protection/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/right-of-access/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Right of Access&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; is a central part of GDPR as it dictates that any individual who you hold data on, has a right to see that data and request deletion. This election campaign, we expect citizens to access this right more than ever as organisations compete for their attention. With NationBuilder’s &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a rel="noopener" href="https://support.nationbuilder.com/en/articles/2309076-how-to-download-a-person-s-data-from-their-profile" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;data download tool&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; this can be exported at the click of a button and processes as necessary.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Use google analytics with consent: &lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Google analytics is a valuable tool for understanding where traffic from your website is coming from and where there is drop-off; plus, it’s  key to maximising user journeys and driving users to action. But in order to be GDPR compliant, you should be asking for analytics consent. This can be done by &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a rel="noopener" href="https://support.nationbuilder.com/en/articles/2363034-set-up-an-analytics-consent-banner-for-your-website" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;setting up an analytics consent banner&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; for your website using NationBuilder tools.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;These are just some of the ways that customers are using NationBuilder privacy tools to maximise their engagement. For more information about the NationBuilder Europe team’s work, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a rel="noopener" href="https://nationbuilder.com/europe" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;please visit our webpage here.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;The information offered here and other NationBuilder GDPR and data privacy-related pages is not legal advice for you or your company to use to comply with the GDPR or other (European) data privacy laws. NationBuilder cannot offer legal counsel. Instead, we are providing information about the steps we have taken to become GDPR compliant ourselves and the product features and services we offer (and will offer in the future) to help our customers use our products in a GDPR compliant manner.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 12:09:28 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Oliver Wells</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/the_first_general_election_post_gdpr</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diary of a candidate Vol.5: “Let’s raise some funds!”</title>
      <description>&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="https://d3n8a8pro7vhmx.cloudfront.net/3dna/pages/47045/attachments/original/1573653733/Candidate-Jackie-days-180_2x-META.png?1573653733" alt="" width="516" height="287" /&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #2f96bf;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;a style="color: #2f96bf;" href="https://nationbuilder.com/journal_candidate_episode_5"&gt;Read this in &lt;span style="color: #2f96bf;"&gt;French&lt;/span&gt; 🇫🇷&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;We are Lison Laissus and Oliver Wells, NationBuilder Account Managers based in the London office. Having worked with many political parties and campaigns, we want to share what we’ve learned for people new to the process. This series is a step-by-step journey of a fictional candidate running for office, informed by our shared experience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 11:42:08 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Lison Laissus</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/diary_candidate_vol_5</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five reasons why leaders use the NationBuilder theme marketplace</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;A bold website design is an integral ingredient for leaders to be successful in their digital campaign. It’s the vehicle for effectively telling a story, capturing the interest of its supporters and broadcasting it to as many humans as possible.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;However, not every leader has the capacity to pursue a custom website theme. A made-to-order design can take weeks to produce and cost thousands of dollars in the process. Although necessary for many organizations, this reality can prohibit causes from launching fast and generating the critical mass of volunteers or donations needed early on. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Enter &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a rel="noopener" href="https://themes.nationbuilder.com/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;NationBuilder's theme marketplace&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;. Launched in early 2019, the marketplace was born of our customers’ desire for more options beyond the &lt;a href="https://nationbuilder.com/stock_themes"&gt;nine stock themes&lt;/a&gt; we provide as part of our standard product offering. Not only did they want more options; they wanted options that were gorgeous, affordable and easy-to-install as well. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Here are the top 5 reasons why leaders can benefit with a theme from the marketplace:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 14:36:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Brian Tippy</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/five_reasons_why_leaders_use_the_nationbuilder_theme_marketplace</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a look at the NationBuilder product roadmap</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week, we launched a better way for you to stay up to date on NationBuilder’s product roadmap. The &lt;a title="Product Portal" rel="noopener" href="https://nationbuilder.com/suggest" target="_blank"&gt;NationBuilder product portal&lt;/a&gt; allows you to see what engineering work is in consideration, what has been planned, and what has launched.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 10:04:12 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jason Meer</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/take_a_look_at_the_nationbuilder_product_roadmap</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gear up to GOTV and give your campaign the edge</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;img title="Advance voting station in Toronto" src="https://d3n8a8pro7vhmx.cloudfront.net/3dna/pages/46932/attachments/original/1571417949/22130538281_f0fa4e6597_c.jpg?1571417949" alt="Advance voting station in Toronto" width="100%"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Election Day is fast approaching in Canada, and many other countries across the world. During the countdown,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; if you haven't finalized your &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://nationbuilder.com/campaign_101"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;GOTV strategy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;, or are still looking for something to increase voter turnout — these resources will set you apart from the crowd.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 13:33:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Katie Angelo</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/gear_up_to_gotv_and_give_your_campaign_the_edge</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Control Panel Redesign: Building the future of our software</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;After &lt;a rel="noopener" href="https://nationbuilder.com/doing_hard_things_together" target="_blank"&gt;months and months of ongoing work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; on the control panel redesign, the limited beta officially launched on February 28th, 2019. At that point, select groups of customers gained access to the new control panel. Slowly, the first hints of much-awaited customer feedback started to trickle in––and it was largely positive.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 12:30:33 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Nelli Veletyan</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/control_panel_redesign_building_the_future_of_our_software</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diary of a Candidate Vol. 4: Empowering your volunteers</title>
      <description>&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="https://d3n8a8pro7vhmx.cloudfront.net/3dna/pages/46494/attachments/original/1565778448/Candidate-Jackie-days-220_2x-META.png?1565778448" alt="" width="571" height="317" /&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://nationbuilder.com/journal_candidate_episode_4"&gt;Read this in French 🇫🇷&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;We are Lison Laissus and Oliver Wells, NationBuilder Account Managers based in the London office. Having worked with many political parties and campaigns, we want to share what we’ve learned for people new to the process. This series is a step-by-step journey of a fictional candidate running for office, informed by our shared experience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 03:35:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Lison Laissus</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/diary_candidate_vol_4</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Control Panel Redesign: Doing hard things, together</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Not only was the recent control panel redesign the &lt;a rel="noopener" href="https://nationbuilder.com/creating_the_future_of_our_product" target="_blank"&gt;largest project NationBuilder had undertaken since its launch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;—it was different from any other project the engineers and designers of Pod Phoenix had previously worked on. Namely, there was no way to release updates to the control panel in parts because they affected every area of the product––meaning that the work would have to be completed, in full, before any part of it went public.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 12:28:13 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Nelli Veletyan</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/doing_hard_things_together</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make your message heard with SpeechKit</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a guest post written by Dennis Sinden, Commercial Director of&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://speechkit.io/"&gt;SpeechKit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;the first all-in-one toolkit for automated audio news publishing. SpeechKit seamlessly creates, distributes, tracks and monetises hyperrealistic audio editions of the news stories and newsletters on your NationBuilder site in seconds.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 12:22:55 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Farz Sokhansanj</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/speechkit</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Control Panel Redesign: The start of a new era for NationBuilder</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;In April of this year, NationBuilder released the most significant update to our software since our launch: a &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a rel="noopener" href="https://nationbuilder.com/new_control_panel" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;full redesign&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; of the main control panel. With the update, we aimed to provide customers with an easier, more seamless platform to navigate as they do the important work of growing their communities. The road to getting these updates out the door was neither short nor simple––but at NationBuilder, we pride ourselves on doing hard things. Especially when it comes to making it easier for our customers to build the future.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 14:42:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Nelli Veletyan</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/creating_the_future_of_our_product</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Strong Customer Authentication (SCA) on NationBuilder</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;The European Parliament’s second Payment Services Directive (PSD2), a piece of legislation regulating how European customers can make payments online, comes into effect on September 14, 2019. As a result of PSD2, many European online payments will require Strong Customer Authentication (SCA), a new set of requirements intended to reduce fraud and make payments more secure through &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://stripe.com/gb/guides/strong-customer-authentication#what-is-strong-customer-authentication"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;two-factor authentication&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Our team is at work updating our NationBuilder &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://support.nationbuilder.com/en/articles/2344217-accept-payments-with-nationbuilder"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;integrated payment processing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; to be SCA compliant in advance of September 14th. In this post, we’ll explain how we’re approaching the project and answer top questions we have received from customers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;What happens on September 14th?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Any new one-time or recurring donations attempted on NationBuilder donation pages may be subject to additional authentication requirements. If a payment requires authentication but the user doesn’t provide it, the payment will fail. Recurring donations that were set up prior to September 14, 2019 are not expected to require authentication.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;img title="Example of SCA Flow" src="https://d3n8a8pro7vhmx.cloudfront.net/3dna/pages/46466/attachments/original/1563907891/SCA_blog_post_-_image.png?1563907891" alt="Example of SCA Flow" width="700" height="369"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;What types of donations will require authentication?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Any payment initiated by a cardholder whose bank is located in the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/European_Economic_Area"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;European Economic Area&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; (EEA) may require authentication, though we expect that any &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://stripe.com/gb/guides/strong-customer-authentication#exemptions-to-strong-customer-authentication"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;non-exempted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; payment in which the recipient’s bank is also located in the EEA will require authentication as well. Put another way – if you are a NationBuilder customer located in Europe, you should prepare for most transactions to require authentication. If you aren’t located in Europe but accept payments from donors in Europe, you should also make sure your pages are set up to collect proper authentication from those donors by signing up for NationBuilder’s integrated processor or our PayPal Express integration before September 14.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;One exemption that we expect most European banks to honor is for fixed-amount recurring payments. For instance, if a donor set up a recurring payment of $10 before September 14, any subsequent payments of the same amount are unlikely to require authentication. Since our recurring donation integration doesn’t yet allow donors to change their gift amount, we expect most recurring donations to process successfully after authentication on the first payment. Once we add the ability for donors to manage their own gifts, we will also give them a way to re-authenticate as necessary.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;How can I make my donations SCA compliant? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;You can sign up for NationBuilder's integrated processor or our PayPal Express integration before September 14. NationBuilder’s integrated payment processing takes only a few minutes to set up and allows you to process donations using the Donation (v2) page type. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;PayPal has also stated that our hosted third-party integration with PayPal Express will be compliant in advance of September 14th. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Our other direct integrations—which allow the donor to complete checkout entirely on your NationBuilder website—will not prompt for authentication after September 14th and as a result, will not be SCA compliant. For any customers who will likely be affected by PSD2 and want to be SCA compliant, we recommend &lt;a href="https://support.nationbuilder.com/en/articles/3278967-accept-payments-with-nationbuilder-gbp-aud-euro-nzd"&gt;signing up for NationBuilder’s integrated payment processing. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;If I want to sign up for NationBuilder’s integrated processing to set up SCA compliant donation forms, how can I do so?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://support.nationbuilder.com/en/articles/3278967-accept-payments-with-nationbuilder-gbp-aud-euro-nzd"&gt;NationBuilder's integrated processor&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;span&gt;powered by Stripe, our payment service provider. NationBuilder's integrated payment processor Express option &lt;/span&gt;is now&lt;/span&gt; open to GBP users and Standard is open to EURO, AUD, and NZD users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Once you have created an integrated payment processing account, you can use our &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://support.nationbuilder.com/en/articles/2477801-donation-page-converter"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;donation page converter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; to upgrade your donation pages to the donation (v2) template, which allows one-time and recurring donations on the same page through our integrated payment processor.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Please note that European cards are defined by whether or not their issuing bank is located in the EEA, which still includes the UK as of this post. &lt;span&gt;There are no gateway or setup fees to use integrated payment processing, and per-transaction rates are as follows: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;EUR: 1.4% + €0.25 (European); 2.9% + €0.25 (non-European)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;GBP: 1.4% + 20p (European); 2.9% + 20p (non-European)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;AUD: 1.75% + 30¢ (domestic); 2.9% + 30¢ (international)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;NZD: 2.9% + NZ$0.30&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Nonprofit rates are not currently supported for beta countries.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 10:49:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jason Meer</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/strong_customer_authentication</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bootstrap 4 now available for custom themes</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting today, all new website themes created with Bootstrap will automatically use &lt;a href="https://getbootstrap.com/"&gt;Bootstrap 4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bootstrap framework has become the most popular way to create highly customized website themes in NationBuilder due to its familiarity and versatility. In addition to being the most popular HTML, CSS and JS library in the world, it also has &lt;a href="https://getbootstrap.com/docs/4.3/getting-started/introduction/"&gt;superb documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m personally most excited about improvements to the NationBuilder page and theme templates also launching with this update, which we believe will make them easier to manage and customize. Frontend developer Levi Beach expands in more detail:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;One of the things that bugged us most about creating new themes from the old bootstrap starter theme was the fact that there were literally hundreds of custom styles that you had to rework or work around if you wanted to really customize the theme. We went from 500+ lines of css in theme.scss to just 171, and we broke out styling for things like Stripe fields, moneybomb, and social sliders so that it’s easier to find, edit, or flat-out remove. We also broke things out into easier to manage includes for things like homepage widgets, avatars, icons, and more.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://support.nationbuilder.com/en/articles/3112336-bootstrap-4-template-changes"&gt;Learn more about key updates to the templates&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We strongly recommend using Dropbox for the best experience building your theme. &lt;a href="https://nationbuilder.com/dropbox"&gt;Learn more about our Dropbox integration&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started, click &lt;em&gt;Website &amp;gt; Theme &amp;gt; New custom theme&lt;/em&gt; and choose &lt;em&gt;Start with Bootstrap framework&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="max-width: 100%;" src="https://d3n8a8pro7vhmx.cloudfront.net/3dna/pages/46410/attachments/original/1561991106/image.png?1561991106" alt="image.png" width="1942" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 08:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jesse Haff</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/bootstrap_4</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The future of your NationBuilder control panel</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="max-width: 100%; display: block; border: 0; border-width: 0px;" src="https://d3n8a8pro7vhmx.cloudfront.net/3dna/pages/46413/attachments/original/1562164401/classic-blog.jpg?1562164401" alt="The future of your NationBuilder control panel" width="100%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://nationbuilder.com/new_control_panel"&gt;new NationBuilder control panel&lt;/a&gt; became available for everyone to try in April, and we've been blown away by the response we’ve received. Most of you reported an easy transition from NationBuilder Classic, and described the new experience as “more intuitive” and “easier to use.” Your incisive feedback made it possible for our team to quickly address the issues you cared about most, resulting in an even &lt;a href="https://www.nationbuilder.design/release_notes"&gt;better experience&lt;/a&gt; today. Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven't tried it yet, you can &lt;a href="https://nationbuilder.com/new_control_panel#ready-to-try"&gt;enable the new control panel right now&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/330777293"&gt;watch a video to learn the basics&lt;/a&gt;. We’ve also launched &lt;a href="https://support.nationbuilder.com/"&gt;updated documentation&lt;/a&gt; to help answer any questions you might have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starting August 5th, the new control panel will be your default experience, and on September 3rd, we will deprecate the Classic control panel.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new control panel is the future of NationBuilder. It’s the foundation we’ll build upon as we continue to innovate, make usability improvements, and take evolutionary leaps in the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can’t wait to keep building it with you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 10:12:37 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jesse Haff</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/the_future_of_your_nationbuilder_control_panel</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diary of a Candidate, vol 3: Tag it!</title>
      <description>&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="https://d3n8a8pro7vhmx.cloudfront.net/3dna/pages/46401/attachments/original/1561543362/Candidate-Jackie-days-240_2x_en.png?1561543362" alt="" width="477" height="265" /&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://nationbuilder.com/journal_candidate_episode_3"&gt;Read this in French 🇫🇷&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;We are Line Kristensen and Lison Laissus, NationBuilder Account Managers based in the London office. Having worked with many political parties and campaigns, we want to share what we’ve learned for people new to the process. This series is a step-by-step journey of a fictional candidate running for office, informed by our shared experience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Lison Laissus</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/diary_candidate_vol_3</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparing a new wave of women in leadership for 2020</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Election season is here. From local to federal, emerging campaigns have already captured media discourse. It's a time that exhausts some and energizes others, but for me, it’s a time of deep awareness of our collective responsibility to be civically engaged. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 10:06:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Cristina Pacheco</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/preparing_for_a_new_wave_of_women_in_leadership_for_2020</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your new NationBuilder control panel is here!</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://nationbuilder.com/new_control_panel"&gt;&lt;img style="display: block; border: 0; width: 100%;" src="https://d3n8a8pro7vhmx.cloudfront.net/3dna/pages/46124/attachments/original/1555590515/0418cp-header.jpg?1555590515" alt="Your new NationBuilder conrtol panel is here" width="100%" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;In February we announced the new NationBuilder control panel limited beta: a redesign of each NationBuilder interface to deliver a more streamlined, consistent and powerful user experience. The initial reaction from those who participated in the limited beta was overwhelmingly positive, and I'm thrilled to announce that as of today, all customers can try the &lt;a href="https://nationbuilder.com/new_control_panel"&gt;new NationBuilder control panel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 06:51:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jesse Haff</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/your_new_nationbuilder_control_panel_is_here</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unrigging the system: Reflections from a weekend in Nashville</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;RepresentUs’s Unrig Summit in Nashville was uniquely collaborative in that it asked attendees to set partisanship aside and connect across party lines. The event brought together moderates, progressives, and conservatives who were aligned on one common theme: the need for reform in American democracy. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 06:42:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Taylor Sayig</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/unrigging_the_system</link>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
