<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Recorded webinars - NationBuilder</title>
    <description/>
    <link>http://nationbuilder.com/recorded_webinars</link>
    <item>
      <title>How to turn your #GivingTuesday donations into a sustainable base of support</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Every year, an incredible amount of work goes into #GivingTuesday campaigns and strategies––but just because the big day of giving is over, doesn’t mean the work is done. In this webinar, you'll learn about the tools and tactics that will help you take the progress you made leading up to #GivingTuesday and transform it into a sustainable base of support for your cause.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 14:19:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Katie Angelo</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/how_to_turn_your_givingtuesday_donations_into_a_sustainable_base_of_support</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated and personalized donation receipts with Facturly</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this video we cover an overview of how Facturly Receipts sends automatic and personalized donation receipts, so you can thank your community, meet your regulatory requirements, and more, for any type of donation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 09:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jesse Haff</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/facturly_webinar_recording</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building community power before, during, and after the UK election with New/Mode - Recording</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this video, we'll walk through how you can use New/Mode and NationBuilder to build community power before, during, and after the UK election.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 07:54:51 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Katie Angelo</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/new_mode_recording</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GOTV best practices to win your election</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you haven't thought about your GOTV strategy, or are still looking for something to give your turnout program a winning edge—watch this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 06:16:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jesse Haff</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/gotv_best_practices_to_win_your_election_rec</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick wins to optimize your #GivingTuesday strategy</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how these quick tactics can take your #GivingTuesday strategy to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 06:16:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jesse Haff</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/quick_wins_to_optimize_your_givingtuesday</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chatbox Webinar Recording - A fully-featured text messaging platform</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this video, we'll walk through the features of Chatbox and how it is a fully-featured text messaging platform helping organizations deliver personalized, hyper-local and data-driven messaging experiences at scale.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 06:15:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jesse Haff</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/chatbox_webinar_recording</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key Tactics in Surpassing your Fundraising Goals</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fundraising, especially if you're running for office, can be one of the most daunting challenges you have to face. So how do the most successful fundraisers consistently hit their fundraising goals week after week, month after month?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 06:13:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jesse Haff</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/key_tactics_in_surpassing_your_fundraising_goals_recording</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turn volunteers into leaders with SupporterBase</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this video we cover an overview of how SupporterBase turn volunteers into leaders and grow your movement with distributed organizing with the NationBuilder platform.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 06:13:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jesse Haff</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/supporterbase_webinar_recording</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn How to Run for Office in 60 Minutes</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whether you're considering running for your local school board, or interested in a future presidential race, this webinar will equip you with the tools you need to step up and lead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 06:12:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jesse Haff</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/learn_how_to_run_for_office_recording</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlock the Power of Your Supporter Data Recording</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What makes today's most impactful organizations so effective? Chances are, they're digitally savvy and making data-driven decisions on a daily basis. This webinar will teach you all you need to know, watch now!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jesse Haff</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/unlock_the_power_of_your_data_recording</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MyActionCenter - an online action center for supporters</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this video we cover an overview of how MyActionCenter enables organizations to quickly deploy an online action center for supporters using the NationBuilder platform.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 14:59:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jesse Haff</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/myactioncenter_recording</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Optimize your Action Center for Supporter Conversion </title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered why some digital action centers are better than others? How do the top advocacy organizations mobilize their constituents to action?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 14:59:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jesse Haff</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/how_to_optimize_your_action_center_for_supporter_conversion</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Build Effective Issues-Based Email Campaigns</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how to build effective issues-based email campaigns that drive supporters to action.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 14:58:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jesse Haff</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/issues_based_email_campaign_recording</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GDPR: An opportunity to better target your people</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how you can use GDPR as an opportunity to better target voters, supporters and other members of the public.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 14:57:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jesse Haff</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/gdpr_targeting</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Secret to Lowering the Cost of Supporter Acquisition</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn simple tips to make your supporter acquisition budget go further by working with NationBuilder.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 14:57:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jesse Haff</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/the_secret_to_lowering_the_cost_of_supporter_acquisition</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New NationBuilder Control Panel Walkthrough</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today we are walking through the new NationBuilder control panel tab by tab.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 14:56:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jesse Haff</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/new_nationbuilder_control_panel_walkthrough</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ecanvasser and NationBuilder - elevate your ground game</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Demo of Ecanvassar and Ecanvasar GO — apps that allow you to send people out in the field and log contacts with results that sync back to NationBuilder.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 14:55:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jesse Haff</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/ecanvasser_and_nationbuilder_-_elevate_your_ground_game</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Putting People at the Center Matters</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how to leverage one fully-integrated system to power all of your engagement and mobilization work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 14:55:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jesse Haff</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/put_people_at_the_center_recording</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HandyNation updates - Event management, canvassing &amp; more</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HandyNation updates - You can now create lists, see who in your database is near you, RSVP people for events and check them in and canvas all on your mobile.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 14:54:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jesse Haff</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/handynation_updates_event_management_canvassing_more</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WinWith.Me - A Facebook Messenger bot-building tool</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Click to learn more about WinWith.Me a Facebook Messenger bot for political campaigns that connects to your nation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 14:54:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jesse Haff</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/winwith_me_a_facebook_messenger_bot_building_tool_recording</link>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
