<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>NationBuilder Customer Stories</title>
    <description>Case studies of parties, nonprofits, advocacy groups and more who've showed us powerful ways to lead.</description>
    <link>http://nationbuilder.com/stories</link>
    <item>
      <title>How party on the rise PTB-PVDA gained 35 seats in Belgian parliament</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;The Workers’ party of Belgium (PTB-PVDA) launched highly targeted phone banking campaigns to get out the vote in local and national elections and become one of the top five parties in Belgium.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 13:46:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jane St. John</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/ptb_pvda</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How political outsider Andrew Yang grew his base and qualified for the 2019 debates</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;This Democratic challenger made the transition from internet meme to grassroots movement and drove early fundraising success by mobilizing his committed fan base, the Yang Gang.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 11:31:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jane St. John</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/andrew_yang</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unite America built a networked infrastructure for independent candidates in U.S. elections</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;What began as an idea in 2013&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; has become a full-fledged movement to disrupt the two-party system in the U.S.—supporting thirty endorsed independent candidates across nine states in the 2018 midterms.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jane St. John</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/unite_america_story</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Are Sikhs organizes to tell the American Sikh community's story</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;An idea-turned-initiative is leveraging powerful storytelling to break down misperceptions of the Sikh community in the United States.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 11:18:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Nelli Veletyan</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/we_are_sikhs</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kerryn Phelps won the Wentworth seat in a historic by-election</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;A nationally-renowned doctor and marriage equality advocate ran as an independent and won a parliamentary seat held by Australia’s Liberal party for the last century.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 11:42:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jane St. John</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/kerryn_phelps_2018</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Marriage Equality campaign inspired Australians to get out the vote and say "Yes"</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;The Australian Marriage Equality campaign engaged millions of citizens through powerful storytelling to participate in an optional vote affirming the rights of same-sex couples—many participating in a political campaign for the first time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 11:37:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jane St. John</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/australian_marriage_equality</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How European Greens created a network for change-makers</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;With a “green wave” moving through Europe, Tilt!&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;serves as a single platform to rally grassroots support for progressive and environmental causes across the continent.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 10:41:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jane St. John</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/european_greens_2018</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Groen makes history in Belgian elections</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;In the span of one year, Groen built best-in-class websites and infrastructure for hundreds of cities and thousands of candidates, using grassroots organizing to engage more green party voters in Belgium than ever before.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 10:04:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jane St. John</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/groen_2018</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>University of California turns students into voters, and voters into advocates</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;UCLA’s innovative pilot program allows students to proactively join the UC advocacy organization while they register to vote, reducing the barriers for participation and leading to exponential growth in advocate engagement across campus.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 10:02:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jane St. John</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/university_of_california</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VolunteerCleanup.org connects South Florida citizens to protect beaches and waterways</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;An eco-conscious Miami couple went from clearing marine debris in their spare time to running Miami-Dade County’s go-to online event hub for beach cleanup projects.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jane St. John</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/volunteercleanup_org</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People's Vote spreads a powerful civic movement throughout the U.K.</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;With record-breaking demonstrations and mass outreach to Members of Parliament, a grassroots coalition continues to amplify the public demand for a People’s Vote on Brexit and gain traction within the U.K. government. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 09:52:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jane St. John</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/peoples_vote</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LivableStreets Alliance accelerates transportation solutions in Boston</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Learn how a five-person advocacy team moved three successful initiatives forward and helped drive a $5 million increase to Boston’s transportation budget.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 13:06:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jane St. John</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/livablestreets_alliance</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Voters Not Politicians mobilized to end gerrymandering in Michigan</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;A nonpartisan organization of volunteers rallied an army of Michiganders to campaign for Prop 2, a statewide ballot initiative to end gerrymandering, and won 61% of the vote.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 11:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jane St. John</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/voters_not_politicians</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AllSaints strengthens customer relationships, one email at a time</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AllSaints harnessed NationBuilder to find a collaborative solution to a challenge all high-end brands face: how do you build mass email campaigns as expertly targeted as they are beautiful?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 10:24:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jane St. John</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/allsaints_email</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maryland GOP created a network model for a whole party to follow</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Maryland GOP built a scalable network with an innovative cost-sharing structure to both reduce barriers to entry for new candidates and share valuable data with their larger party.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 14:24:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jane St. John</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/maryland_gop</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How NYC Votes boosted civic engagement for local elections</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;The New York Campaign Finance Board used an inquisitive, data-driven approach to inform, engage, register, and drive voters to participate in the important election for NYC mayor.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 17:04:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jane St. John</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/nyc_votes</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apex Clean Energy forges a path for wind farms around the US &amp; Canada</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Apex Clean Energy is leveraging a powerful network and strategic digital outreach to advocate for renewable energy—overcoming organized opposition and paving the way for a growing number of successful wind projects.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 10:34:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jane St. John</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/apex_clean_energy</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Randall Woodfin beat a 7-year incumbent &amp; became one of Birmingham's youngest mayors</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With a fresh approach to politics and strong grassroots support from his community, Randall Woodfin inspired thousands of young people to vote for the first time in a municipal election.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 10:21:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jane St. John</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/randall_woodfin</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lone Star Veterans Association harnessed community for hurricane relief</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;A veterans affinity group used NationBuilder to turn a post-Harvey text outreach into a full-scale search, rescue, and relief effort for the Houston community they’d served for years.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 09:28:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jane St. John</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/lone_star_veterans_association</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Jacinda Ardern became New Zealand's youngest female prime minister</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The New Zealand Labour party paired a strong digital infrastructure with a resounding message to beat their fundraising goals and rally a nation around their new leader.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 21:59:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jane St. John</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/jacinda_ardern</link>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
