<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Strategic resources - NationBuilder</title>
    <description/>
    <link>http://nationbuilder.com/strategic_resources</link>
    <item>
      <title>Habits of highly effective fundraisers</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;At NationBuilder, we create software designed to equip and empower leaders to tackle the breadth of challenges they’ll face in growing, engaging, and inspiring their base of supporters to take action—from the most basic tasks like identifying their supporters, sending emails, and creating webpages, to complex targeting, analysis, and strategic communications. That means we’re always striving to generate and stay on top of the latest research into what makes the organizations who lead the pack truly successful. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;So, in the competition for people's attention, time, and money, what do the most effective fundraisers do? As NationBuilder’s head of strategy, I have witnessed thousands of charitable organizations and advocacy initiatives of all sizes, raising money across a variety of sectors—and I wanted to share some of my insights on what the highest performers have in common, and which strategies contribute most dramatically to their success.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Look to your people for more than money.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;The days of putting your supporters into silos—donor, volunteer, advocate—are over. Don’t assume that people want to engage in one activity alone. As it turns out, fears about not &lt;em&gt;bothering&lt;/em&gt; your base, or reserving your asks for the all important donation requests, are unfounded. In fact, we found that donors who were asked to engage in other activities as well—for instance, volunteering or engaging on social media—made donations 60% larger than those who were only asked to donate.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; &lt;img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="https://d3n8a8pro7vhmx.cloudfront.net/3dna/pages/44976/attachments/original/1531161894/Hilblog-engage-supporters-green-2x.png?1531161894" alt="Hilblog-engage-supporters-green-2x.png" width="433" height="293" /&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;More specifically, nonprofits received the largest donation amounts from donors who first signed a petition, volunteered, or attended an event. People who completed one of those activities before donating, gave an average of $40. Compare that to the $25 from donors who donated first.* And the impact isn’t just on one donation. Engaging your supporters in more diverse activities likely means they’ll give more&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;often&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; Political campaigns, for example, engage their donors in other activities first over three times more often than the average nonprofit in our study. And they receive &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;double&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; the average number of donations per donor.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;The takeaway: Robust small donor programs benefit from offering multiple ways for donors to participate and creating many paths to engage would-be donors among their base.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;*All featured statistics are based on an aggregate, anonymized data study from our community. This particular statistic pertains to customers on our Leader and Organization plans that received at least one donation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:47:27 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Hilary Doe</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/habits_of_highly_effective_fundraisers</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why you should forget social media and focus on organizing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;There was a time back in, I want to say, 2012, when my Facebook feed was entirely content from Upworthy: feel good videos of people performing &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="attrlink url author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;&lt;a class="attrlink" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.upworthy.com/watch-an-entire-team-of-teenage-football-players-do-something-very-unexpected" target="_blank"&gt;acts of kindness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="attrlink url author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;&lt;a class="attrlink" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.upworthy.com/watch-this-grocery-store-erupt-in-song-for-the-man-the-entire-world-loved" target="_blank"&gt;flash mobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;, and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="attrlink url author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;&lt;a class="attrlink" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.upworthy.com/bullies-called-him-pork-chop-he-took-that-pain-with-him-and-then-cooked-it-into" target="_blank"&gt; anti-bullying&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="thread-737990571919929983228743 author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;dvocacy. Those were the days of movement building from viral content and Change.org petitions. It was a year after the Arab &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovvlncz80zz84zz88zz90zz67zjkz66z55z75z9z83zz66zsdtdo2xz72zz77zcz80zz65zz71z"&gt;S&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;pring had demonstrated the power of using digital tools for lightning-in-a-bottle organizing. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="thread-183256609983258066462962 thread-948820625634386659037052 author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="thread-183256609983258066462962 thread-948820625634386659037052 author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovw8oz82z8vz78zz72zuz78zz70zwgz81zz122zz67zz73z7nz76zz79zju2z77zz74zz83z5z65zc1"&gt;t the time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;, I was running a consultancy that helped non-profits, politicians, and unions build these movements online. There was a pervasive belief that visibility was all we needed to succeed. We chased views&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="thread-950760161780147144845934 author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt; likes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovw8oz82z8vz78zz72zuz78zz70zwgz81zz122zz67zz73z7nz76zz79zju2z77zz74zz83z5z65zc1"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt; and shares like they could change the world&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="thread-785311416033046852929245 author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;—&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;and sometimes they did. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;The internet today is a different place. Every minute feels like a year. The &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="thread-402400413085584422670793 author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt; cycle moves at a break-neck pace. Something viral this morning is forgotten&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovw8oz82z8vz78zz72zuz78zz70zwgz81zz122zz67zz73z7nz76zz79zju2z77zz74zz83z5z65zc1"&gt; by&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt; this afternoon. Never mind the 24-hour news cycle—there are almost 90,000 seconds in a day&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovw8oz82z8vz78zz72zuz78zz70zwgz81zz122zz67zz73z7nz76zz79zju2z77zz74zz83z5z65zc1"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt; and people who spend a lot of time organizing online can feel every one of them. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;As the content cycle quickens, we’re also learning that clicks and views &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="thread-890528451198934932413366 author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt; not the panacea we thought. Social media companies &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="thread-954448215382497493854538 author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;chased ad dollars&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt; relentlessly, and incentives to exaggerate viewership and engagement metrics led to &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="attrlink url author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;&lt;a class="attrlink" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.fastcompany.com/40581630/yet-again-facebook-is-being-sued-over-inflated-video-metrics" target="_blank"&gt;shady business practices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;. The people we depend on are &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="attrlink url author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;&lt;a class="attrlink" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" href="https://trends.google.com/trends/explore?q=how%20delete%20facebook&amp;amp;date=all&amp;amp;geo=US" target="_blank"&gt;moving to platforms &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;where they’re &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="attrlink url author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;&lt;a class="attrlink" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" href="https://trends.google.com/trends/explore?date=all&amp;amp;geo=US&amp;amp;q=instagram" target="_blank"&gt;harder to reach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt; and content is harder to share. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;Over the past decade, I’ve worked with a lot of organizations who rely almost exclusively on these platforms to hold their communities together. While I’ve encouraged them in the past to diversify their tactics, that advice has never been more important than &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="thread-164517128257718092080712 author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=" author-d-1gg9uz65z1iz85zgdz68zmqkz84zo2qovwsz71zvz86zz66zvz90zz79zz78zfz122zz89zz71ziz76zkoz122zz84zz74zz76zpbqgsz76zz72zz79z2"&gt;t is now. A decade ago, social media platforms were novel. Today, they’re the lifeblood of many extraordinary organizations. What can we do if—or when!—our people leave for greener pastures? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 13:04:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Amy Stuart</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/forget_social_media_and_focus_on_organizing_in_2019</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to turn your cause into a movement</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At NationBuilder, we’re constantly examining emerging high-stakes movements that garner international attention. What makes some more effective than others, and what are the digital tools and features that contribute most to their growth? In my experience working on campaigns for nearly a decade on four different continents, I’ve concluded that the success of a campaign often comes down to three components—the appeal of its mission, the scalability of its campaign tactics, and the deep, shared commitment of the people involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a mission relevant to the moment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;Movements and new parties that see exponential growth often do so because they seize the moment in the heat of national debate and fearlessly make the decision to lead. Rather than getting bogged down in processes, they start with a single issue or mission. Digitally, this can look like a basic NationBuilder website with a couple of prominent actions for visitors to take, such as signing a petition or making a donation. In the midst of a conflict, this simple starting point allows movement-builders to find other supporters who care about their cause.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 13:21:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Line Kristensen</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/how_to_turn_your_cause_into_a_movement</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Start a grassroots campaign for your favorite candidate</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;As more and more candidates enter and leave the race for the the 2020 presidential election, it’s easy to get caught up in the unfolding drama and speculate as you wait for a clear frontrunner to emerge. For instance, who could be an inspiring ‘first’ if elected? Who’s raised the most in small dollar donations over the course of their campaign? Who seems to be gaining or losing the most momentum? Though it’s tempting to watch as a passive observer, if there’s someone whose candidacy has captured your inspiration, now is the time to step up and create something powerful with your support.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Alex Stevens, Sorcha Rochford, and Jay Godfrey are all campaign experts who worked as organizers across the political spectrum before joining the team at NationBuilder, the software platform used by thousands of campaigns around the world. Here are their insights on why your grassroots organizing can be impactful and how you can get started—even if it’s your first time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you should take the initiative&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;For any one candidate’s campaign to succeed, they’ll need the committed grassroots support of people from all over the country who are willing to corral their own friends and family to organize on the ground—wherever they are, wherever it’s needed, and all the way up until election day. As the last few election cycles have proven, a traditional, broadcast-based campaign that relies predominantly on the national party won’t cut it (at least not on its own).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the people who aren’t officially running yet. The most compelling case you can make to get someone to run is to show them how many people will be in their corner if they do. Some of the most &lt;a title="Jagmeet Singh Customer Story" rel="noopener" href="https://nationbuilder.com/jagmeet_singh" target="_blank"&gt;high profile campaigns&lt;/a&gt; that have run successfully on NationBuilder started with viral supporter petitions encouraging a candidate to enter the race. In those cases, as soon as the candidate officially announced, they could quickly mobilize the &lt;a title="Jacinda Ardern Customer Story" rel="noopener" href="https://nationbuilder.com/jacinda_ardern" target="_blank"&gt;small-dollar fundraising support&lt;/a&gt; that’s so critical to amass early on in a campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What you can do that the national campaign can’t&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;The first priority for the candidate’s national campaign has to be winning early primaries and caucuses in the states where they can. Any resource-strapped campaign (as most are) won’t be able to send field staff to larger, later states until much further along in the race, so the work you do knocking on doors, handing out pamphlets, and creating buzz in your local community will help create the infrastructure of on-the-ground supporters your candidate will surely need down the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the independent group you create will be able to organize faster, with more agility, and with greater freedom to speak directly to the people around you about what you know matters to them than the official campaign ever will. You can communicate authentically without having to navigate the complex priorities and PR challenges that face large campaigns. When the national campaign team does arrive in your area, they’ll find a groundswell of support that’s stronger for having grown organically, based on the relationships you’ve built.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 13:20:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Jane St. John</author>
      <link>http://nationbuilder.com/how_to_build_a_grassroots_campaign_for_your_favorite_candidate</link>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
