<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog - Volt</title>
    <description/>
    <link>http://www.voltbelgie.org/blog</link>
    <item>
      <title>Volt to Run for EU Parliament in Record Eight European Countries</title>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pan-European party to compete in Belgium, Bulgaria, Germany, Luxembourg, the Netherlands, Spain, Sweden, and the UK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No other party has ever managed to campaign in so many nations with one and the same programme&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 22:41:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Lewin Schmitt</author>
      <link>http://www.voltbelgie.org/volt_ep-elections_announcement</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Volt België presenteert kandidatenlijsten</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;De Belgische nationale afdeling van de pan-Europese partij Volt heeft officieel de kandidatenlijsten en het verkiezingsprogramma voor de opkomende regionale, federale en Europese verkiezingen goedgekeurd.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 20:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Lewin Schmitt</author>
      <link>http://www.voltbelgie.org/volt_presenteert_kandidatenlijsten</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Volt bestuur verkozen tijdens ledenvergadring</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Op 8 en 9 December zijn Volt leden en vrijwilligers van over heel België bijeengekomen in Kortenberg voor een intensief tweedaags congres met workshops, strategiesessies, speeches en daarna de stemming voor twee belangrijke partijbeslissingen: aan welke verkiezingen neemt men deel, en met welke voorzitters per regio. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 23:25:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Lewin Schmitt</author>
      <link>http://www.voltbelgie.org/2018-12_press</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Damian's 1st anniversary blog</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When Andrea invited me for a lunch to discuss his newest ideas, I never thought it would result in such a drastic change for me. In fact, I just thought it would result in a free lunch. But, you know what they say: there is no such thing as a free lunch.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A little more than a year later, I’ve moved to another continent, I’ve gathered speeding tickets all across Europe, I’ve spent nights on the floor of people’s flats I’ve met the same day (thanks Volt NL :-), and I am unsure about where my free time has gone – but I don’t mind at all. Actually, I am extremely happy about it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And here are the reasons why.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Volt is needed.&lt;/em&gt; I am writing this blog post in a cafe in Warsaw, where we are preparing for the meeting of the young Polish team. As we were walking towards this cafe today, we passed the former Ghetto. As a German in Poland this is a powerful reminder for me on how vital it is that nationalist tendencies should be countered. Volt’s idea on how to do this is rather simple and compelling: Excite people who pragmatically want things to be better, both in politics and society; create the political platform for them to be able to improve them; and build a credible counterforce to the political stagnation and the populist right-wing tide of AfD, Front National, Lega, etc. But not only populism demands swift action. There are many more issues ranging from old age poverty, youth unemployment, climate change, inefficient administrations, immigration, to discrimination that require attention. This movement for me is about the aim to make better political decisions, propose better policies to relieve the suffering of so many in our society and improve life for all. This movement is about making a change.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Volt is passionate&lt;/em&gt;. The meeting tonight will be organized by a new, small, and active group of people in Warsaw, and it will be impressive to see how these new Volters will again engage with strangers, how they will share their passion and their will for change. Over the last year, I saw this happening multiple times in different places, and I am extremely happy that so many of us got inspired to spend our time, thoughts, creativity, and passion for something that is - in the end -  driven by positive hope for society. Whatever happens, this is the first success for Volt – having provided a productive platform for passionate people to take up responsibility for their society.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Volt is focused.&lt;/em&gt; On our trip here in Warsaw, we have Mike with us, our technical guru (Mike prefers &lt;em&gt;Director of Technology&lt;/em&gt;, but honestly, I prefer guru). Mike is convinced that this will work, that Volt will work. I am generally a sceptic, but this time I am with Mike. I believe that Volt will work and I would not be spending time on it if I would doubt that. I truly believe that if we continue to follow our idea with passion, we will improve the lives of many across the continent. We will gather the necessary crowd, raise the necessary funds, acquire the necessary knowledge, find amazing MEP candidates, run an impressive campaign, enter the European Parliament and build the structures that will carry us well beyond 2019. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, this is my view on Volt after a year. I could not be happier about having had that first lunch. I could not be happier about the people I met, starting from Andrea and Colombe to Hanna, Magda, Philipp, Eileen, Boris, Dominik, Natalia, and Mike from the Polish startup team – and every one of you I had the chance to meet over the last year. If like me, you believe that we can actually open a positive chapter of the history books, and that we can make a difference for those who are suffering, get on your feed and dig deep into whatever work you are currently doing for Volt. Then, think about how we could do it better. Help Andrea and me build a pan-European party that is worth existing, that brings about real change.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:43:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.voltbelgie.org/1st_anniversary_damian</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Andrea's 1st anniversary blog</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 year ago, minutes before the launch of Volt, I was sitting in an anonymous university cafè, nervous as I had never been before. Sitting at my table was Damian – back then a friend I convinced to help me in return for a free lunch, and now Volt’s Vice-President – while Colombe was with us over the phone – back then a human rights defender, and now Volt’s Policy Lead and even more into human rights, if possible. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The three of us planned this day for a long time. The naïve, ambitious, extremely promising idea I put together in the previous months that those two fools idealists helped me to structure, was ready to go live. “Ready”… I mean, we had a Facebook page, a website that I had taught myself to design, a few friends ready to support the launch, absolutely no budget, and a huge passion and willingness to change politics and the future of Europe. What else do you need to start a pan-European movement?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;The root of the idea&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“And then the Brexit happened…”. I might have repeated this sentence 500 times already, in every corner of this continent, and even beyond. However, when I get asked why on Earth did I decide to start this project, I cannot avoid to mention that warm Thursday of June. Back then, I was still working in the private sector, and I would have never thought about jumping into politics myself, at only 25 years old. However, when the results of the vote became clear, I understood that the European Union, and all the values connected to it, were in danger for the first time in my life. An open and safe society, the possibility to feel part of something bigger than my nation, and the dream of a constantly evolving continent were crumbling, and no political faction was standing up to defend them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;That same day I realized that we were at a turning point in history. Either we –meaning all the ones that were tired of witnessing their towns, countries, and continent decline – started to get active, or in a few decades there was not going to be much to defend anymore.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;The preparation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A national party? A European movement? This dilemma tormented me for a few weeks. On one side, as an Italian, I saw a great opportunity to create a new political force in the depressing political landscape of my country. However, I shortly realized that to really change things, to propagate a vision, and to create a real long-term project that could improve this continent for good, something bigger than a national political party was needed. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Building a European movement might not seem that innovative. Some have tried, often with poor results. However, building a European, transnational movement ready to produce local solutions in a European framework, this is truly innovative. The idea of jumping right in the local level, building teams in tens of cities, enabling people to participate and have a voice from Sicily to Brandeburg, and not only from Paris to Berlin, is a game-changer. Often, European political actors (exactly as European institutions) are miles away from citizens. This is why we built a movement  made of citizens, local realities, cultural differences, real problems, shared solutions, and an incredible amount of efforts to avoid to become an “only-English-speaking-I-love-Europe” movement. Hundreds of events, 50 city teams, 15 Facebook pages, and a website soon to be in 8 languages later, we can safely say that we chose the right path.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;The launch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Going back to that morning, it is now clear that the only thing that could lift up a project with no names and no funds, is the power of the idea itself and the passion of those standing behind it. I remember the exhausted faces of Colombe, Damian, and all the others that pushed the first launch (Guglielmo, Giulio, Salome, Federico(s), Filippo, Niccolò, Eugenio) after a full day of social media spamming, website fixing, applicants allocation for interviews, and many other activities that hundreds of people are now taking care of. Without a few crazy heads, Volt – back then still Vox – would have crushed in a matter of hours. Thanks to their passion and the energy of people that gave everything they could for an idea, here we stand. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;The growth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Since then, it has been a wonderful ride. We had thousands of new members, hundreds of events, tens of countries joining, 4 crowdfunding campaigns, 3 pan-European gatherings, 2 websites, 1 rebranding, and an infinite amount of big &amp;amp; small successes that defined the identity of this movement, motivate its people, and enlarge its great potential.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;From that day, many of us lost a lot of free time, hours of sleep, even some money, but none lost the passion to contribute to a vision that might change our continent, forever.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;The present&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Almost 3000 members and supporters spread over 24 European countries, press coverage in the most prestigious newspapers of the continent, video-conferences every day to organize activities, and still the same young and less young faces working to improve Europe. Still no big names, no much funds, and the same irrational belief of being part of something that could lead to the biggest political revolution of this century.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;After 365 days, we can all be proud of what we achieved, proud of not having changed our identity, proud of collaborating despite our cultural differences, proud of the solidarity that we show when our members have a difficult time, proud of fighting with all our energies to improve our societies.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;The future&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Volt is increasingly professional, has more and more members and expertise, and a growing notoriety. We cannot foresee where all of this will go, but I can personal guarantee that I will continue to give everything I can to this project.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the milestones that the movement has on its radar:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;Paris Retreat in May,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; gathering hundreds of Volters to prepare our future moves.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;Somewhere in Europe in October&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;, launching our 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; General Assembly and our European campaign.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;In at least 7 European countries in May 2019&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;, running for European elections.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;A future in every corner of this continent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;, providing real solutions and fighting for the causes we believe into, from the smallest town, to the tallest palace in Brussels.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Join the Change. Many did already, and I cannot be more grateful for what they are pushing Volt to achieve.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Thank you,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Andrea&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:43:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.voltbelgie.org/1st_anniversary_andrea</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Colombe's eerste jubileum blog</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A personal history of Volt &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exactly one year ago, we launched Volt (see “&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.volteuropa.org/the_battle_for_our_future"&gt;The battle for our future&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;”, “&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.volteuropa.org/salvation_at_your_doorstep_why_we_desperately_need_volt"&gt;Salvation at your doorstep: why we desperately need Volt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;”). In honour of its first anniversary, let me take you on a short journey retracing the key steps and remembering why we are spending every awaken moment fighting to make this dream a reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;June 23, 2016: Brexit happened. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, this was not such a surprise considering the campaign and the situation at hand. However, it was a further blow to a concept - the EU - that is believed to be the best means to achieve peace, security, the highest standard of living, and the respect of human rights, among others (see “&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.volteuropa.org/a_call_for_europe"&gt;a call for Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;”). This came in the context of the rise of populism in the world, the rise of inequalities within and between countries and the rise of hate crimes, among other (see “&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.volteuropa.org/european_populists_and_how_to_fight_them"&gt;European Populists and how to Fight them&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;”). For these reasons, Brexit impacted many people more than they thought it would. While complaining over the phone with Andrea about its impact on our lives the morning of the 23&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt;, he said something that stuck with me: “&lt;em&gt;let’s stop complaining and actually do something that will safeguards what we hold dea&lt;/em&gt;r.” Yes, sure great idea, but how? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this moment onwards, the idea of Volt started to emerge&lt;em&gt;: what about a movement that we would start in a single country, and then grow in others?&lt;/em&gt; No, this would not have achieved our aim. &lt;em&gt;What about a European movement?&lt;/em&gt; No, because Europe is a means to achieve our aim, but cannot be the sole solution: some local problems need local answers. Slowly, with the help of Damian, we started to move in the direction of a movement that would not only exist at the European level, but also in every country on the European territory, to tackle issues at all levels, use best practices to find real solutions, and actually bring about change. As none of us were politicians, one thing that quickly became clear to us is that &lt;strong&gt;we should not only aim at changing Europe and its countries, but also the way politics is done. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I was still a bit hesitant. Andrea convinced me by telling me this: “&lt;em&gt;Look, I hope we will succeed, but even if we don’t that is not what matters. What matters is that we lay the groundwork to show that this is feasible, that many different countries can work together for a better future for all, and that we can do politics in a good way&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very quickly, some basic concepts and values were laid down that we agreed we would work for and around, including the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our aim is to help people, and we shall act accordingly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We stand for the respect of human rights, and will not ever compromise on them. This is why human rights are part of our fundamental and foundational values.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We will not back down from a fight just because it is unpopular, difficult, or would make us loose votes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We will apply our own principles to ourselves: it is very easy to say that we want government, countries and others to behave in a particular manner, but who are we if we don’t lead by example?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We will do this the proper way: we will not play into populist narratives, we will not be an undemocratic movement, we will not be provocative just for the sake of inflaming people, we will not campaign without a programme and strong policies, and so on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;March 29, 2017: the launch and our first year&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the help of a few friends, we launched Volt the day of the triggering of article 50, a year ago. We launched a pan-European progressive movement, present at the European level and in many countries, that wants to revolutionize politics and the way it is done.  Volt is neither left or right, neither conservative or liberal: it goes beyond all those classifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s our pitch, but what does it actually mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pan European: we are pan-European because we aim at being present in every European country, and at the European level: we believe this is the best way to affect change, by being able to tackle issues everywhere and together. This is what makes us unique: we can inspire ourselves from other countries, look for solutions together, collaborate, and come up with the best possible outcomes, for all. We also all come under the Volt umbrella and can set priorities to fight for together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pro-European: we are a pro-European movement, yes, but that does not mean that we blindly want to move towards a closer Union. We are pro-European while understanding that many aspects of the EU need to be drastically reformed, challenged, and bettered (see our flagship policy “&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.volteuropa.org/unite_europe"&gt;Unite Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;”). For us, Europe is a mean and not an end in itself: our aim is to help, to build on what we have and change what needs to be changed in order to ensure that no one is left behind, that all are guaranteed equal rights and the best standards of living, that we will live in a better world. One of the means to achieve this is, we believe, Europe (as we can see with its track-record). However, it is not the only one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Progressive: we advocate and work for progress, change, and social reforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neither left nor right: we use best practices. This means that we will use a model that works as long as the policy respects our fundamental values, that we check how it will impact those who will be the most affected by it, that it is evidenced-based and follows scientific evidence. We don’t want to cluster ourselves in traditional party clans, as it is unfeasible for a movement that is in more than 23 European countries: apart from the fact that we use best practices, one type of classification does not mean the same thing in different countries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big part of who we are is the fact that we want to run on a programme. As a pan-European movement, the question was however raised of how to have coherent programmes at all levels (European, national and local). This is what was decided:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Policies and programmes are first created at the European level, under our &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.volteuropa.org/vision"&gt;5+1 challenges&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Those are broad guidelines that leave room for adaptation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;National chapters translate, adapt, prioritize and if needed create new policies. National policies have to be consistent with European guidelines and with other countries: countries can reach a goal in different ways, but they cannot directly contradict one another.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any policy created at any level has to comply with our fundamental values (mainly the respect of human rights and others), be evidence-based when evidence exists, and have a ‘vulnerability check’ (meaning verifying the impact it would have on the part of the population it would impact the most). &lt;span&gt;Finally, it should follow best-practices when possible: &lt;/span&gt;we never pretend we know everything but look at what works, how we can implement it, or whether we need a drastically different solution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All of our policies follow the process we set out as a movement, to ensure that Volters can vote and express their opinion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this is possible thanks to the amazing members we have in our teams: they are from all sectors, all ages, and some are experts in their fields and are at the forefront of change in their professional lives. However, whenever we lacked the competences and expertise to craft certain policies, we held off until we had people with such competences willing to help or join, rather than given an ill-advised response, recognizing that we needed to know more (which is also why we reach out to experts to help and review our policies and use best practices).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;29 maart 2018: de toekomst.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Het is nu een jaar geleden dat we Volt lanceerden. Van een 'beweging' van een Italiaan, een Fransman en een Duitser, waar zijn we nu?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We bevinden ons nu in meer dan 24 Europese landen, in meer dan 50 steden, onze &lt;span&gt;communiteiten&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div&gt;niet meegerekend. We hebben meer dan 3000 supporters en 1500 leden. We zijn gestart met een &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/VoltEuropa/?hc_ref=ARSQ3anhtLU9i_rRbAFeSCYJhzz5Ln119_rIzsNuBgVvqyJxj_f0HMl-Raphm1F2_o8"&gt;Facebook pagina&lt;/a&gt;, we hebben er nu meer dan 20.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We hebben de beweging in Luxemburg opgenomen, we zijn een politieke partij in Duitsland geworden en we werken er in alle andere landen aan om hetzelfde te doen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We hadden 3 pan-Europese evenementen (Juli - Milaan; oktober - Berlijn; januari - Boekarest) en zal onze 4e in mei in Parijs hebben. We houden onze eerste ronden van nationale vergaderingen in heel Europa en hebben er meer dan 200 gehouden.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wij begonnen uitgebreid persaandacht te krijgen (&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.liberation.fr/planete/2018/02/15/nous-voulons-creer-le-premier-parti-paneuropeen_1629888"&gt;hier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Loopsider/videos/vb.424922021243063/483530968715501/?type=2&amp;amp;theater"&gt;hier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.corriere.it/esteri/18_febbraio_21/i-millennial-volt-vogliono-dare-scossa-ue-rilanceremo-l-europa-1f79e9fa-16eb-11e8-b630-41a05c9e9642.shtml"&gt;hier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nrc.nl/nieuws/2018/02/20/we-willen-nieuwe-energie-in-europa-brengen-a1592969"&gt;hier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naast deze indrukwekkende aantallen hebben we ons gericht op een gezonde interne structuur, die ons in staat stelt zo democratisch, effectief en rechtvaardig mogelijk te zijn. Hiervoor hebben we onze eerste interne verkiezingen gehouden, gestemd over ons beleid (en dat blijven we doen) en een taskforce in het leven geroepen die het goede voorbeeld geeft en met richtsnoeren en voorstellen komt voor de beweging om ervoor te zorgen dat we onze waarden naleven, dat we inclusief zijn en dat we niet alleen voorstellen doen, maar die ook daadwerkelijk uitvoeren binnen de beweging. Het bestuur van Volt Europa mag bijvoorbeeld geen mensen hebben die dezelfde nationaliteit hebben, en alle drie de bestuursleden mogen niet van hetzelfde geslacht zijn. Daarnaast zijn we bezig met de oprichting van een externe instantie voor conflictoplossing, die tot taak zal hebben claims van ongepast en discriminerend gedrag, geweld en/of seksuele intimidatie te beoordelen, volgens ons beleid "Bridge the Gender Gap", dat pleit voor dergelijke maatregelen op de werkplek.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dus wat is de volgende stap?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hebben grote plannen: we willen om te beginnen in mei 2019 in het Europees Parlement worden gekozen, in ten minste zeven landen en met 25 leden van het Europees Parlement, om de eerste onafhankelijke pan-Europese partij te zijn die ooit onafhankelijk is geweest.  Dat betekent niet dat we alleen bij de Europese verkiezingen zullen zijn: we zijn van plan om tegelijkertijd nationale, regionale en lokale verkiezingen te houden. Wij zijn niet van plan om gekozen te worden: wij zijn van mening dat wij als onafhankelijke beweging in staat zullen zijn om echte veranderingen tot stand te brengen en ons programma op een verenigde manier op Europees niveau uit te voeren, terwijl wij hetzelfde doen op nationaal en lokaal niveau.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Terugkijkend op de laatste jaren van het werk aan Volt en na met velen van u te hebben gesproken, blijf ik erop terugkomen dat we niet uit het oog mogen verliezen om welke redenen we dit allemaal doen. Hoe kazig het ook klinkt, de reden is om mensen te helpen en van Europa een betere plek te maken, zo niet de wereld. Met Europa bedoel ik niet de EU, maar elk land, elke regio, elke stad. Ja, we zijn al zoveel gegroeid en hebben veel potentieel, maar wat is het waard als we weer een politieke partij worden die alleen maar honger heeft naar macht en roem? Wat ons maakt is dat we er om geven. Het maakt ons zo veel uit dat duizenden mensen in hun vrije tijd gratis werken om ervoor te zorgen dat er daadwerkelijk iets verandert. &lt;/strong&gt;Daarom is volt zo uniek en hebben we het op onze evenementen gezien. De reden hiervoor is dat we hier allemaal om dezelfde reden zijn, en we het in eerste instantie misschien niet altijd eens zijn over de middelen om dit te bereiken, maar we het wel eens zijn over het doel. Dit vertaalt zich in de praktijk door altijd tot een compromis te komen en een oplossing te vinden, ondanks het feit dat met meer dan 100 mensen uit meer dan 20 landen, met verschillende achtergronden en leeftijden, uiterst actuele onderwerpen worden besproken. We debatteren, we discussiëren, we zijn het er niet mee eens, maar we vechten niet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Telkens als ik u allen ontmoet op onze evenementen, kom ik met een enthousiasme, motivatie en hoop die opwindend is (ja, onze naam is heel toepasselijk). Daarvoor wil ik u bedanken en u nog een gunst vragen: verlies nooit deze passie, geef nooit op, vergeet nooit waarom u dit doet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:43:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.voltbelgie.org/1st_anniversary_colombe</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Volt 1st anniversary</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;--- One year has passed since Volt started... so we, Colombe, Andrea and Damian, reflected a bit on what happened since we first started. It was a cold winter day in 2017... ---&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andrea's 1st anniversary blog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1 year ago, minutes before the launch of Volt, I was sitting in an anonymous university cafè, nervous as I had never been before. Sitting at my table was Damian – back then a friend I convinced to help me in return for a free lunch, and now Volt’s Vice-President – while Colombe was with us over the phone – back then a human rights defender, and now Volt’s Policy Lead and even more into human rights, if possible.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The three of us planned this day for a long time. The naïve, ambitious, extremely promising idea I put together in the previous months that those two idealists helped me to structure, was ready to go live. “Ready”… I mean, we had a Facebook page, a website that I had taught myself to design, a few friends ready to support the launch, absolutely no budget, and a huge passion and willingness to change politics and the future of Europe. What else do you need to start a pan-European movement? &lt;a title="Andrea's blog" rel="noopener" href="https://www.volteuropa.org/1st_anniversary_andrea" target="_blank"&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colombe's 1st anniversary blog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reflecting on the last years working on Volt, and having talked to many of you, what keeps on coming back to me is the importance of not losing track of the reasons for which we are doing all of this. As cheesy as it sounds, the reason is to help people, and make Europe a better place, if not the world. By Europe I do not mean the EU, but every single country, region, city and town.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes, we already grew so much and have a lot of potential, but what is it worth if we become just another political party that is solely hungry for power and fame? What makes us us is that we care. We care so much that we have thousands of people working for free in their spare time to ensure that things actually change. &lt;a title="Colombe's blog" rel="noopener" href="https://www.volteuropa.org/1st_anniversary_colombe" target="_blank"&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Damian's 1st anniversary blog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When Andrea invited me for a lunch to discuss his newest ideas, I never thought it would result in such a drastic change for me. In fact, I just thought it would result in a free lunch. But, you know what they say: there is no such thing as a free lunch.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A little more than a year later, I’ve moved to another continent, I’ve gathered speeding tickets all across Europe, I’ve spent nights on the floor of people’s flats I’ve met the same day (thanks Volt NL :-), and I am unsure about where my free time has gone – but I don’t mind at all. Actually, I am extremely happy about it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And here are the reasons why. &lt;a title="Damian's anniversary blog" rel="noopener" href="https://www.volteuropa.org/1st_anniversary_damian" target="_blank"&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;and... newly published: Liuliu's 1st anniversary blog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am a Chinese student in New York who took on a crazy journey with Volt, this young European political movement which led me to Rome, Berlin, Milan, Paris and many more places to come. What am I doing here? &lt;a title="Liuliu's blog" rel="noopener" href="https://www.volteuropa.org/liuliu_my_story_with_volt" target="_blank"&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:42:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.voltbelgie.org/1st-anniversary</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The counterproductivity of the terms race and racism </title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Volt strives to ensure that no one is discriminated against, or subject to violence, based on ethnicity, national origin, descent and/or skin colour. Despite existing legislation, prejudice, unequal treatment and social exclusion are still part of people’s daily lives within Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Volt is advocating for the removal of the following terms ‘race’, ‘racial discrimination’ and ‘racism’ as the concept of race is socially constructed. Indeed, scientifically there is only one human race (Homo sapiens). On this merit, our policy against discrimination shall consist of the following discriminatory basis: ethnicity, national origin, descent, skin colour.     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of our Volters, Aza Lemmer, went into more details and gave his personal opinion on the issue, which you can read below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often read articles about discrimination: the most prominent terms are race and racism, people being discriminated because of their “race”. Even Art.1 GW of the Dutch constitution has the term race cemented, as well as in international law, for example the United Nations’ Universal Declaration of Human Rights speaks in art.1 about “All human beings are born free and equal in dignity and rights” naming one human species as a singular race, although in art. 2 it uses the term race with a plural meaning. We often speak about race and/or racism within legal frameworks and doctrine but why is this so?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A scientific perspective &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a scientific perspective there is only one human race (Homo sapiens). We share the same phenotype yet we still use the terms race and racism in our legal instruments and daily life. Why are we giving validity to a term and definition that has no scientific backbone? Laws exist to be based on facts and not on faulty terms. Though by saying this, the term/concept of race and/or racism does exist in a social construct, thus in social science. It dates way back to the 17th century coming from colonialism to categorize a group of people as a lower “race”. While some scientists believed that there was indeed racial differences within humans in the 19th century, there were also scientist like Dr. Du Bois who believed that it was incorrect from a biological perspective and that the science of racial differences was used for pseudoscience to give validity for the social constructed concept of race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we want to end “racism” and have legal instruments and frameworks against racialization they work counterproductive as it actually keeps the term and concept of race and racial categorizing of groups alive. Consequently, giving it validity. From a historical perspective, words have a huge impact on society. Labeling things as good or bad has an effect on how we think and behave because we realize it in everyday life and practice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social concept of race &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the #blacklivesmatter movement we saw some African-Americans defining them self as the black “race” which gives validity to the term and ideology of racial categorizing although it is not their intention to do so. In my opinion, they are not aware of the counterproductivity and are in fact victim of the social construct term of race. Starting in the 1950’s African-Americans fought for their civil rights as they were racialized/discriminated because of their “race” which led to the African-American civil rights movement(1954-1968) and in that context the definition of racism had a good outcome by giving them civil rights which they did not have before based on institutionalized racism. Yet we are living in 2018 and till this day some of us still think there are racial differences within the human race or use the term race in official papers – this keeps the social constructed term of race and racism alive. While in fact in modern day we can speak of discrimination based on ethnicity, skin color, geographic groups and etc. as there is no scientific justification of race within humans. Therefore, such racism is an invalid term. Unfortunately, we have normalized the term race: it is conditioned within our societies. We even call some people black while we all should know the skin color black does not exist in humans, but that is another discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Validity of race in our legal frameworks &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is of course ethnicity as a ground of discrimination and other physical or non-physical attributes. Instead of naming it racism which is in fact scientifically incorrect, we should define the term discrimination better in our legal frameworks and get rid of the terms race and racism in official documents and legal frameworks. As long as we are using the terms for the good or bad we keep categorizing and the concept of race will remain alive. Looking at the UN Declaration of Human Rights it tries to avoid the concept of race. However, looking at the following sentence “without distinction of any kind, in particular as to race, colour or national origin” it is contradicting because it acknowledges the social concept of race within its legal framework and thus gives validity to it. Another example is Art. 1 of International Convention on the Elimination of All Forms of Racial Discrimination which also mentions the term race while having the terms racial discrimination in quotations marks for referring to as the concept of race again contradicting use of the term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Redefining discrimination &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some may argue that you give a free card for “racism” by removing the terms race and racism from the law as some still think that you cannot have a penalty code without mentioning the word race or racism even though the penalty code for discrimination should be sufficient enough. I find that removing the terms of legal instruments will lead to a more refined and socially and biological accurate definition of discrimination. As mention earlier law should be based on facts. Norway is leading the way in this matter by removing the terms race and racism from their national laws. Their Anti-Discrimination Act, which entered into force in 2006, speaks only of discrimination based on ethnicity, national origin, descent and skin color as a substitute of the terms race and racism. As Norway acknowledges that the use of those terms within legal frameworks works counterproductive as it gives an unintentional social side effect by legitimizing and validating the concept of race in a social construct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we truly want to stop racism, we should start by not giving it any validation in our laws and remove the terms race and racism. And we can make steps moving forward from thinking in boxes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:42:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.voltbelgie.org/the_counterproductivity_of_the_terms_race_and_racism</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Margrethe Vestager: The Volt Interview</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some have called her ‘the most powerful woman in Brussels’. Now famous for fining Google $2.7 billion and finding that Apple owed the Irish state $14.5 billion in unpaid taxes, Competition Commissioner Margrethe Vestager has brought a new dynamism to the European Union. Over Skype, I asked her about her work dragon-slaying mega-corporations and how movements like Volt can slowly gain the hearts and trust of Europe.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Margrethe Vestager:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;It’s a little extraordinary, seeing you like this, because normally I would ask you if you’d like a cup of coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Noah Vickers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;I would have said yes! Thank you so much for agreeing to speak to us, it’s a huge honour. You’ve become famous, in the last year particularly, for your work taking on massive corporations like Google and Apple. And we live in a time of great Euroscepticism - I’m part of a movement trying to slowly counter this. How would you explain the relevance of your work to a Eurosceptic? What is it that you are able to do, and I suppose, by extension, that the EU is able to do, that a national anti-trust agency would struggle to do, or perhaps in some cases, would be less willing to do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MV:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Well, I think it’s just an illustration that there are some things that we can do together, that you cannot do alone, because I don’t even think that a national competition authority would be able to do it -  it is a cross-border issue and it concerns the entire European market. The strength of what we do comes from the fact that we are, give or take, 500 million people, who are doing this together. Just as well as there are things we can do together, there are things that you can do in each member state that are relevant there. But I think that the miracle of developing a democracy as we have done, I think that is ideal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t change the fact that we need a regional part of the democracy and a national part, but we would truly miss having our European democracy as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NV:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;So, would you say that corporations like Google or Apple have more reason to be afraid of a united Europe perhaps than the member states themselves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MV:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Well I indeed think so, because, actually right now we are trying to empower the national competition authorities so that they can better protect citizens (and their computers). Because what we see, is they don’t have the same powers as we have, for instance, to give out fines that are sufficiently high to have a deterrent effect. And it has a different impact, when you do things together. I see this very clearly because I used to be the Minister of Economics and the Interior in Denmark, and we were not even close to starting to ask questions of some of these corporations about what they were doing – about their whereabouts, about their taxes, about whatever it would have been, so I feel personally very strongly about the fact that we have decided to have competence together – that is what is changing things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NV:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Speaking of working together, the movement I’m part of, Volt, are trying to be the first truly pan-European party (rather than just parties working in blocs in the European Parliament, co-operating with one another). You are of course yourself a member of a political party, but if you had no political ties, and you were starting from scratch, in a similar position, in establishing a pro-European, pan-European party – what would you do? What would your advice be to us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MV:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Well, it’s a very tricky question, because I think one of the reasons why so few people are a member of a political party, (in my own country, it’s less than 5%), is because I don’t think they find it relevant. They have so many other things to do, and yet at the same time, you find massive numbers of people who engage in NGOs, in being a volunteer at an elderly home or helping refugee children do their school work, you know, all kinds of stuff. So, I think it would be important to be not only a political movement, but also to be a movement that encourages you to engage in your local society, in order to make those ties between engaging in a local democracy and needing a European democracy – necessary if we are to grasp the bigger problems, because I think it’s that combination that we lack. Also, to be able to kind of shortcut the national movements that are using the European democracy as a scapegoat, for what they themselves cannot achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NV:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Absolutely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MV:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;I think there has to be an element of engaging with other people directly. Otherwise I think you may find that you aren’t making sense or being relevant to someone volunteering, helping refugee children or visiting elderly people, to say, “well, I can do this and it makes sense for this person” (the child or the elderly person). But, it’s important for them as well that the European democracy is working, because when you see the political parties in Europe, such as my one, the ALDE group, it contains so many different parties, and the groups themselves contain very different families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NV:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Yes, I was surprised to see that the Prime Minister of the Czech Republic’s party [Andrej Babiš’s ANO 2011] are part of ALDE as well and they’re known for being somewhat Eurosceptic, whereas in the UK we tend to think in the context of ALDE as being centrist, liberal pro-Europeans because we have the Liberal Democrats here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MV:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Well of course, the Liberal Democrats are members of ALDE and the Group President of ALDE in the Parliament is a federalist if anyone was ever a federalist! So, you find that it’s very diverse family. It is not a coherent movement and it has only just begun to have individual members, so I think you have to do something else if you want a pan-European movement to appear, to take into account that a lot of people want to&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;do something.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;They don’t just want to dream and discuss and decide, they also want to&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;do&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our interview continued in the video below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe class="embedly-embed" src="//cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FOjK5DiAEdsM%3Fwmode%3Dtransparent%26feature%3Doembed&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DOjK5DiAEdsM&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FOjK5DiAEdsM%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;key=e23856ccc1f011e0b5e44040d3dc5c07&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" width="600" height="338" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:42:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.voltbelgie.org/margrethe_vestager_the_volt_interview</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seeing the Bigger Picture (Part 3)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the third and final part of the "Seeing the Bigger Picture" series by Louis Drounau, a journey through history that shows how a more united Europe would benefit us all (read the first two parts&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="/seeing-the-bigger-picture-1"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;and&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="/seeing-the-bigger-picture-part-2"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this final article, Louis challenges us to recognise how it is only by coming together in unity that Europe will be able to preserve and nurture its shared, thousand-year old identity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Identity first, administration second&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having read the&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="/seeing-the-bigger-picture-1"&gt;first&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;and&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="/post/seeing-the-bigger-picture-part-2"&gt;second&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;part of my series, we know that political structures are constantly changing and that this change should not be feared. The question now is: what kind of change should we welcome and encourage in Europe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer: the one that helps us&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;promote our values and reach our goals&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting back to our previous analogy, as a child inevitably changes with adulthood, we should welcome any change that makes him a better person. We should therefore welcome change that makes us a better society. But what defines a “good society”? As societies, we must judge our actions by whether they respect and promote our values and goals. So what are our values? And which are our goals?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the humanist, these would be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Human rights&lt;/em&gt;; because, without them, we succumb to tyranny&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Democracy&lt;/em&gt;; because it allows us to choose freely what we want for ourselves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The rule of law&lt;/em&gt;; to ensure that the previous two are respected by all and for all&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In countries where the rule of law is enforced, citizens’ rights are protected and a vibrant democracy can flourish. If proper laws do not exist or are not respected, citizens live in a state of arbitrariness and unbridled competition – a competition that, by default or by design, will favour the most powerful. In such systems, might is right: the weak is left without the shield of the law, while the strong forces his will. This is precisely what the rule of law aims at preventing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Our anarchic state of international law favours power relationships, tax evasion and terrorism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent centuries, most States have made great progress in securing the rule of law on their territory, developing formal judicial and institutional mechanisms and codifying laws and customs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the same is not true of the international system in which we live. While international law continues to grow, it lacks a proper enforcement mechanism from an overarching public authority. Its application relies on voluntary State compliance. And, while States can be invited to comply – through their self-interest or naming-and-shaming –, they cannot be forced. In this system, militarily or economically powerful nations are free to force their will on other, smaller players, regardless of their supposed independence. The nominal sovereignty of weaker countries does little in the face of power-based relationships that play in favour of the big and strong. This global chaos also works as a ladder for non-State actors, including multinational companies and terrorist groups, too happy to pit States against one another − for instance to avoid paying taxes or to benefit from the lack of cross-border law enforcement cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reform yourself before others force you to do so&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European countries face the inevitable prospect of becoming medium or small players on the global scene and compete against bigger powers. Our representatives and citizens would do well to consider the words of EU High Representative Federica Mogherini:&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“European countries are divided in two kinds: the small ones and the ones that have not yet realised they are small in the world of today.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the demise of European colonial empires and the progressive development of the Global South has reshuffled the distribution of powers worldwide, and European nations now find themselves in positions slightly more in line with their respective populations and sizes. And we should make no mistake about it: continued efforts to eradicate global poverty and to promote global development, as well as a favourable demography, will continue to help poorer countries catch up on their European counterparts, as they should for the benefit of all. What will European countries do separately when India, Pakistan, Brazil, Ethiopia or Nigeria catch up with their untapped potential? Germany, the most populous of European States, is only the 16th most populous country worldwide; its 1.1% of the world’s population pale in front of China’s 18.4%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Looking for unity beyond our own borders&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence, we are faced with the risk&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;to lose not our nominal sovereignty, but our actual capacity to freely choose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;to the benefit of countries that may or may not share our values. What are our options in this regard?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, we could decide that the safeguarding of our national institutions and sovereignties is paramount; that maintaining our nation-States the way we know them and think they ought to remain takes precedence. We aim to stay politically independent, organise our own political life and make our own decisions. And, as others grow, we shrink to sovereign nothingness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, we could decide that our identity lies in our history and in our values rather than in our institutions, and that these can be placed above our administrative and political structures. We could acknowledge that our national military, political and economic powers are insufficient to compete against stronger powers, and realise that our ability to choose freely is slowly but surely eluding us. Consequently, we recognise that&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;we would better preserve our identity and freedom and promote our values by coming together willingly amongst like-minded countries&lt;/strong&gt;, rather than discard any more of our decision-making power to stronger and potentially hostile powers. In the exact same manner as the various parts of a country stand stronger by belonging to united national structure, so would European countries stand stronger under a unified federal structure. There is truth in the saying “united we stand”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key element to understand is that there is no historical predetermination for a people to live together within the borders of the same country − people did not pre-exist their countries, history and life together made them a people. Had history unfolded differently, we would be different people, and it would all seem just as natural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Today’s nationalist fight for what yesterday’s nationalists fought against&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class="w-richtext-align-floatleft"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The choice to form a united political community, which for millennia rested upon the fate of battles or the willingness of kings and emperors to conquer or marry, is now open to popular decision. We are free to change our political structure and community. All we need is to want it and get our representatives to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some say that our national histories are too unique and our cultures too different to ever form a European federation. Saying so, however, would be admitting that we are forever limited by our past and the prisoners of history. If it were so, and if any evolution was limited by where we come from, there would be little to fight or hope for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s nationalists forget that the countries they wish to preserve or “restore” – the very structures they see as the embodiment of our identities – are what yesterday’s nationalists fought against. Members of the French&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;Front National,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;who today see themselves as patriots and glorify France’s enlightenment, should remember that, before them, others who also called themselves patriots, resolutely fought against the same enlightenment. They too pretended to defend the true France “as it had always been” and should remain. Of course, future generations will not fail to judge their efforts just as misguided as those who fought to maintain tribal divisions, absolute monarchy, or colonial empires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;By coming together, we safeguard our identities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A wilful decision to come together as a European Federation is by no means a renunciation of who we are; it is not the end of our national histories and identities. It is&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;recognising that we share common values with our European neighbours and that, by coming together, we are better able to preserve them.&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Just as our shared Roman-Hellenistic roots have not vanished after the disappearance of the Greek city-States and of the Roman Empire, our national histories and values will endure in a unified Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="w-richtext-align-floatright"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the United States: while we usually see them as one identical people, Americans will readily proclaim that the people of New York live differently from the people of California, and that the people from the red hills of Georgia are not those of the snow-capped Rockies of Colorado.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such diversity in a country the size of a continent can, and should, be enshrined through well-thought institutions. The same way that our regional traditions have not disappeared through the establishment of the nation-States, so will our national differences and characters endure in a unified Europe. It is left to us to design strong, democratic, and representative institutions, adapted to our specificities, that will ensure the respect of our freedoms and differences, and let us live stronger together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Let’s no longer define ourselves by a line on a map&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this brief review, I aimed to explain that what has changed will inevitably change again, whether we wish it or not. The preservation and affirmation of our identify simply cannot go hand-in-hand with the strict immobility of our socio-political structures.&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who we are&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;or&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;what we are&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;is far more than a simple line on a map or a reserved seat at an international conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The choice is now ours: we must decide what we wish to make of our future and recognise, as others have successfully done before us, that, before any meaningful reform of the anarchic global system, coming together as like-minded people, with shared values and liberty for all, is the only way to ensure the survival of our European identity&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;About the Author:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Louis currently works for the United Nations in Nairobi, Kenya. Before that, he also worked for the UN in Côte d'Ivoire and New York, and, among others, with the European Commission on political affairs and with the Council of Europe on anti-money laundering activities. He is a strong EU and world federalist and passionately debates socio-political topics. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:42:44 +0200</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.voltbelgie.org/seeing_the_bigger_picture_part</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Work</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work and Labour markets are changing dramatically.&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Digitalization, globalization, and demographic changes are transforming their nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This offers&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;challenges and opportunities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;for Europe, but and sure we all experience growing&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;polarization and disruption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;of the status quo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;On one side, involuntary unemployment&lt;/strong&gt;, in particular youth unemployment, is at an alarming level in many regions and poses a dramatic threat to social cohesion in the EU and a majority of its States;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;On the other side,  people desiring more flexibility&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;for their work-life balance and for self-employment find ever growing opportunities to arrange their life accordingly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must understand and manage both.&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is one of the key priorities for all European citizens&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;and traditional parties are slow to grasp the urgency of this matter  and to propose viable solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To manage well this transition towards the ‘Future of Work’, the EU will have to build a solid Social Pillar as a foundation for a ‘Social European Union’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Volt advocates an EU wide “Marshall Plan on Work and Life-Long Employability” as one program to put such Social Union into practice, with the following components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Flexibility and Work-Life Balance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volt supports a&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working Time Choice Act&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;and wants to become the recognized political voice for the growing number of self-employed, start-ups, crowd and gig workers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Life-Long Learning for Employability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volt supports a strategy to move ‘&lt;strong&gt;From an Unemployment to an Employment Insurance’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;with a re-orientation towards a preventive scheme focused on maintaining employability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volt advocates&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the immediate adoption of  ‘Erasmus Pro’&lt;/strong&gt;, to give every year 200,000 apprentices the opportunity for a two-year long apprenshiceship in another EU country.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volt Europe supports&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Individual Long-Term Accounts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;that support life-long education, boosted by a&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;periodic Bonus for life-long learning and re-training&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Social Protection and Basic Income&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volt envisions universal social protection and an adequate income to become a core pillar of EU Policy making. This requires a long-term perspective combined with short-term actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volt advocates the&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;strengthening of existing Guaranteed Minimum Income (GMI) schemes across the EU, initially with at least a modest goal of converging on a minimum poverty threshold of 40%  &lt;/strong&gt;of the equivalent national median income („extreme poverty“), with the schemes conditioned not only on a traditional job search, but also on a possible development of a new business or even an (unpaid) social activity (like mentorship, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volt endorses the idea of a&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start Capital for every young person&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;in the EU. Such start capital can be seen as a Social Inheritance, that enables a young person to develop its talents, chose a career or start up a business, independently of the social status and wealth of the parents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volt supports&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;large scale experiments with unconditional basic income (UBI)&lt;/strong&gt;, to provide a solid knowledge basis to decide on the merits of this novel approach to social protection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The position of Volt, here summarized, is the result of the discussion and participation of all our members and experts. We recognize that the issue is very complex and in continuous evolution. We therefore welcome comments and ideas from  all interested people!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please review our draft policy paper and discover more details on our proposals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;on Flexibility and Work-life Balance, Life-long Learning for Employability, Social protection and Basic income, as well as the rest of our vision and program:&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a rel="noopener" href="https://s3.eu-west-2.amazonaws.com/voxeurope/Future+of+Work.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We wait for your comments and ideas&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:42:43 +0200</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.voltbelgie.org/the_future_of_work</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seeing the Bigger Picture (Part 2)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the second part of the "Seeing the Bigger Picture" series by Louis Drounau, a journey through history that shows how a more united Europe would benefit us all (read the first part&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="/seeing-the-bigger-picture-1"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this second article, Louis explains how it is normal to fear change and to be attached to what we’ve always known. But at the same time, the possibility of a change for the better should be encouraged and regarded as an opportunity for us to seize.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why are we so obsessed with our borders?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Part 1, we discussed the never-ceasing, disruptive changes in socio-political structures and borders that have affected our countries throughout history. With so many changes, what is it that makes us so attached to our present countries?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Trump’s “America first” policies to&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="/the-battle-for-our-future"&gt;Brexit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;to endless quarrels at the United Nations, both&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;governments and citizens are currently eager to protect their national sovereignty&lt;/strong&gt;, seemingly an ideal of independence and shield against outside interference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While States often enter into bi- or multilateral treaties, they do their best to maintain their national prerogatives. Of course, for some themes, like the Right of the Child or prohibition of biological weapons, it may be relatively easy to reach a cross-border consensus. But, for a multitude of&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="/causes-youth-unemployment-in-eu-and-eu-policies"&gt;other measures&lt;/a&gt;, such as limitations on conventional, nuclear weapons or financial regulation, States are suddenly not so keen on shared goals anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best example for this? The construction of the European Union: despite a heavy corpus of common norms and regulations, States have so far stayed far clear of a political union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Stability through predictability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class="w-richtext-align-floatleft"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have previously discussed the demise of Alexander the Great’s empire. Why do we not mourn it? Why do French people neither lament the Roman invasions nor the fall of the same Roman Empire? And how come the strong opposition to the Federal Constitution in the United States in the late 1780s still made way to a passionate nationalism today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is simple:&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;because we now take all of this for granted&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social interactions rely on predictability. They work best when individuals know and abide by a set of social norms. This&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;predictability implies stability&lt;/strong&gt;: if society’s norms were to change regularly and substantially, there’s no way individuals could internalise and respect them. Therefore, social norms are more prone to&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gradual evolution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;than complete overhauls. Their changes usually result from a long-term dialectic between conservative and progressive camps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly,&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;socio-political structures pursue durability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;to secure the social interactions of their citizens. Their institutions tend to evolve slowly over time. Sometimes, however, a breaking point is reached and a revolution is inevitable. Once the revolution is over, society seeks a new equilibrium and structures itself around a new set of norms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As societies, we are therefore naturally, and irrationally, attached to the structures we belong to – both at the local or national levels. We see them as the bedrock of the social interactions that we wish to maintain. Still, if our system were to change, we would eventually grow just as attached to it until we considered it the norm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Socially, this constant pursuit to preserve and celebrate current structures is a basis for the development of traditions and the insistence of a group to preserve its identity. In the case of nation-States, this penchant helped give rise to nationalist feelings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Strong national attachment = strong short-sightedness?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the idea that an independent country like Italy or Germany would cease to exist seems unthinkable. But many forget that these countries did not exist as they do now a mere 200 years ago, and many more European countries, particularly in Central and Eastern Europe, were created in their present political form even more recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="w-richtext-align-floatright"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, we feel a strong emotional attachment to these structures − strong enough to die and kill for them throughout history. An attachment that seems to grow stronger with greater knowledge of and increased civic involvement in them. Yet, we easily forget the structures that came before them and often lasted much longer. Thus,&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;we take our countries for granted&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;and refuse to consider their possible disappearance or otherwise evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like us, our predecessors took for granted their own countries, kingdoms, and empires. And while, in practice, handover to another royal family often hardly affected the population, the threat of invasions was often feared as the end of their world. A glimpse into history makes it easy to realise that all did not turn out for the worst, and that we are now generally better off than our ancestors were. Maybe our own reluctance to changes in our sovereign States is not so well-founded after all, either?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It’s the end of the world as we know it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it actually mean for a State to be sovereign? What does it mean for a people to be independent? Put simply, sovereignty is the ability for a group of people to make its own choices according to its goals and values, unconstrained by outside forces. From a&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;realpolitik&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;perspective, national sovereignty means independence from other States and non-State institutions. That’s for the theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an interconnected world, however, national sovereignty is increasingly restricted by the economic power of and a dependency towards outside actors − from States to private multinationals. Indeed, what good is it to be nominally independent from third-parties, yet unable to freely make your own choices because of economic constraints? To be at liberty to follow any path, yet remain unable to bear the consequences of these choices? You are like a man choosing to live alone in a forest because he is independent and free; in effect, even when we are independent and free, we choose to live in societies because we rely on and deeply need each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="w-richtext-align-floatleft"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we look to the future, two main possibilities present themselves: mankind ceases to exist, either through war or major environmental degradation, or we manage to continue on. In this latter scenario, it seems both historically and logically impossible that our current nation-States would endure the way they are, forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow or other, our countries&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;continue to evolve: some will change in their institutional form or geographical reach, while others will disappear and new ones take their place. With an open-ended future, it may take decades, centuries, or millennia but it&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;will&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;happen. Overall, it is fair to say that every single one of the structures we know will end or change to the point of being unrecognisable. No more United States, no more China, no more France − at least, not as we currently know and cherish them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s not be fearful of these changes; after all, historical cycles are natural parts of life. We have witnessed them in the past and things haven’t turned out so badly. Like a child growing into an adult and an adult evolving over time, social structures won’t lose their identity but evolve. Only the strict opposition to change – like a child refusing to grow up – is destined to failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By focusing on maintaining our countries intact, by prioritising form over content, we are destined to become a thing of the past, sacrificing our identity and values for the sake of our borders or institutions. Indeed, this is&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;to say that every change is for the best, and progress is never a straight line; but opposing the very idea of change is a vain effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prospects that our nation-States will evolve and may one day disappear should not be feared and blindly opposed – after all, as we have seen, the thousand-plus-year-old French monarchy disappeared and it is this disappearance that gave way to a more just republic. On the opposite,&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;this prospect of change should be envisaged as an opportunity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="/to-all-europeans-to-all-who-are-bold-brave-to-all-the-innovators"&gt;we must seize, guide and encourage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:42:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.voltbelgie.org/seeing_the_bigger_picture_part_2</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seeing the Bigger Picture (Part 1)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the first part of the "Seeing the Bigger Picture" series by Louis Drounau, a journey through history that shows how a more united Europe would benefit us all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this first article, Louis asks us to take a step back, to consider the massive changes that have been occurring in the socio-political structure of the European nations for centuries. And to realize that change is not as scary as it might seem at first glance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;All for one and one for all? How European politics were shaped over 2.000 years ago&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The choice to shape a political community, which for most of human history remained out of reach for the common man and rested instead upon the outcome of battles and on the willingness of kings and emperors to conquer and to marry, is now open to popular decision through democracy.&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citizens are free to choose the size and shape of their political community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;– to come together or to separate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yet, we rarely do so&lt;/strong&gt;. We amend the laws that govern us but leave intact the polity itself: few changes in borders and few political unions ever take place. Why is this? Let us first take a step back and see how most socio-political structures have already changed through history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Each structure rises, grows - and falls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We learn it at school but often fail to notice: socio-political structures have constantly&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;come and gone throughout history&lt;/strong&gt;. Empires, kingdoms, city-States have risen, grown, and fallen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;«And when Alexander saw the breadth of his domain, he wept for there were no more worlds to conquer.»&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time of his death in 323 BCE, Alexander’s empire was considered to encompass the whole known world, from Greece in the West to India in the East. Now, what happened to Alexander’s empire? What is left of it today? Following Alexander’s untimely death, the empire simply brittled and&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;broke apart&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we bring this closer to home, the Roman Republic (and later Empire) is a prime example, having ruled most of Western Europe and the Mediterranean for centuries and extending, at its peak, from Ireland to regions of the Arabian Peninsula. Like Alexander’s before it, the Roman Empire eventually broke up, splitting in two, and saw its Western half dissolve in the 5th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although comparatively brief, Charlemagne’s 9th century empire brought together most of Western Europe for the first time since the Romans. Likewise, it later&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dissolved into competing kingdoms&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly after, however, the Holy Roman Empire picked up the mantle and lasted until the early 19th century, meaning that for over eight hundred years, most of Central Europe was included, one way or another, into one common political entity. The Austrian and later Austro-Hungarian Empires endured for over half a century each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even structures we know and can relate to have changed enormously.&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before France was Gaul&lt;/strong&gt;, encompassing much of continental Western Europe; Gaul was progressively conquered and joined the Roman Empire. It then took centuries after the fall of the Western Roman Empire for Frank tribes, coming from nowadays Germany, to conquer growing parts of what is today the French territory and set up what would become France.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over that long coalescing process, entire regions would switch hands, not only among the aristocracy but also externally: Aquitaine, a large portion of the South-West, was an English possession for over three hundred years. For centuries, France's borders moved ceaselessly in Europe and even reached parts of Africa, Asia, the Americas and Oceania in the second half of the 19th century, until a painful decolonisation process in the 1960s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond its territory, the political system of a socio-political structure can also drastically change. Continuing with the example of France, the country was a centralised and increasingly absolutist monarchy for most of its history. In 1789, it was the theatre of a popular revolution, became a brief republic, toyed with several collegial forms of government, became an empire, re-established a monarchy, once again became a republic, then once more an empire, and finally stabilised as a republic under three major (yet regularly amended) constitutions with widely differing institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Different century, same story&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focusing instead on a given geographical area, we can observe the same,&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;continuous waves of change&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;in ruling structures over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the death of Alexander, Asia Minor – or Anatolia, the territory of modern-day Turkey – saw the rise of several dynasties, including the Attalids and Seleucids, before joining the growing Roman empire for six centuries. In the 11th century, Seljuk Turks started overrunning the Anatolian peninsula before submitting to the Mongols who were themselves later absorbed into the Ottoman Empire. It would take another five hundred years and the Ottoman’s defeat during the First World War for the Turkish State to appear roughly as we know it today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fast-paced historical review shows how much change has already impacted Europe; the same is true for each of the provinces conquered by Alexander the Great and, truly, one for each of the corners of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why do socio-political structures change?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of these reviews is to make vividly clear that the list is endless of socio-political structures, of all sorts, that ruled parts of the world for long periods of time and are no more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many a reason brought these changes about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Military strength&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;first come to mind. Empires and kingdoms would grow larger and more powerful until they lost to a stronger foe, leading to boundary modifications or complete disappearance; sometimes, they may even come to lose to a weaker one, after having withered away internally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Civil strife&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;and discontent with existing structures can lead to the break-up of large ensembles or in drastic internal reorganisations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other, exogenous factors also come into play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rise of new ideologies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;– republicanism, democracy, Leninism, Maoism – has led to complete overhauls of State institutions and radically affected political structures. The first 1917 revolution in Russia swept away over four hundred years of tsarist history within a single week; in China, the struggle between the nationalists and the communists led to the&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;de facto&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;separation of the country into two separate units.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changing social norms&lt;/strong&gt;, such as the growing difficulty of regimes to violently suppress dissent in the face of their public opinion, and the advent of technology, including the emergence of widespread photography in the media, played a strong part in the unfolding of decolonisation processes and other revolutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;We have always been looking for common institutions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, history also offers examples of socio-political structures deciding to come together and creating new,&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;common institutions&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polish-Lithuanian Commonwealth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;is a good example, as the two countries, following several agreements, merged through the Union of Lublin in 1569. The Union lasted for over two hundred years and only broke apart when the repeated partitions of Poland by its neighbours erased it from the map of Europe between 1795 and 1919.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, the thirteen&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;North-American colonies&lt;/strong&gt;, progressively established from the beginning of the 17th century, decided, following the War of Independence, to come together in a common political structure through the Articles of Confederation of 1777.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, in&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Europe&lt;/strong&gt;, following the mass suicide of World War II, the process of European integration began with the Treaty of Rome, in 1958, and has been ongoing ever since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We therefore see that the history of socio-political structures is not a long line of quiet evolutions into the countries we now know. It is marked by the&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;continual creation and creative destruction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;of structures that ruled for hundreds of years and periodically came to an end, making way for newer players, either unwillingly or as a response to a new environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many others, Alexander’s empire, while long gone, has not disappeared from memory and, to this day, its legacy continues to exert a lasting influence on its former territories and on their people. We have not forgotten it: we remember its existence, recognise its achievements, and yet we do not think of mourning it. Simply, with time, we have moved on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Let us shape the change for the future&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us take a step back to understand what the inevitable changes in socio-political structures really means: it means that the current nation-States will not always stay as they are. It means that, over the long run, the fixed borders we grew up with will, one way or another, not endure. It means that we should be open to think about a stronger Union, more fitted to the future of Europe and the challenges ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our small European countries, on their own, are shrinking in population and relative economic power. The rise of developing countries and re-balancing of economic relationships is natural and should be welcomed. It also means that, alone, none of us will be able to make our voice heard. We, as Europeans, have to finally ignite the fire of change and get together, to show the world that there are no barriers, no differences, and no horrors of history that people cannot overcome to ensure a brighter future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we should not be afraid to do so:&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Change is going to come anyway&lt;/strong&gt;. Let us embrace it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:42:40 +0200</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.voltbelgie.org/seeing_the_bigger_picture_part_1</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A call for Europe</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As stated in this previous &lt;a href="https://www.volteuropa.org/starting_from_italy"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, it is necessary to reform the European Union in order to create a stronger Italy. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Equally, any other Member State needs to support the reform of the EU in order to grow. Indeed, the future of all Member States is deeply linked to the one of the continent as a whole.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fully functioning European Union provides great advantages for its Member States. Among many other benefits, the EU&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gives companies access to a market of 500 million people, an area with a GDP comparable to the one of the United States, and supports its citizens in traveling, learning languages, and working abroad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allows member states to have a significant voice on the international stage, where they face the competition of larger and more populous economies (e.g. China and India), whose population is quickly increasing (e.g., Russia, Brazil, and Indonesia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Represents the most effective way to strengthen Member States’ national defense, in a historical moment where links with traditional allies are weakened – such as the U.K. and the U.S.- and external threats are growing (e.g., international terrorism).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unfortunately, in its current shape, the EU has lost most of its effectiveness in supporting the growth and prosperity of its Member States&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. The inability of the European institutions to deliver on their most fundamental tasks –  fostering economic performances of those members that accepted the highest degree of integration (i.e. Euro Area), resolving internal crisis (i.e. migration flows) or giving a more significant weight to Europe on the international stage (i.e. the European irrelevance during the Syrian crisis) – has been perceived by citizens, reinforcing the disruptive political trends currently rising across the continent.  These flaws have paired up with long-lasting negative perceptions of the EU (e.g., a huge bureaucracy, democratically “distant” from the voters). &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The European institutions are failing to achieve one of the most fundamental tasks they have been created for, namely tackling those issues that Member States alone have difficulties in coping with&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Therefore, it is necessary to drive structural reforms to modernize and keep alive those institutions that molded our continent over the last 60 years&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Some political factions are periodically asking for reforms in the EU. However, in the current contest true change seem difficult (if not impossible) to achieve. Not only has the European Parliament (the one truly democratic body of the EU) only limited power, but the European political parties are mainly alliances of national parties with heterogeneous objectives and agendas, often only collaborating to nurture collective benefits (e.g., refunds).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The European Union is in real danger&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. On June 24, 2016, the EU suffered its biggest drawback in decades, arguably even bigger than the failure of the European Defense Community in 1954 or the recent rejection of a European Constitution (2005). For the first time in its history, the European Union is contracting, having lost on the same day (i) the second biggest economy in Europe and the G7 fastest growing member in the last three years, (ii) a nuclear power and permanent member of the UN security council, (iii) and a country with an unrivaled diplomatic network in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;If we do not fight back, the elections in France, Germany or Italy might put an end to the European dream.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Volt in every Member State, to save Europe.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A truly European movement has to be built from people that believe, advocate, and work for the same ideals and objectives, similarly inclined in every national context. Having a shared agenda and a common direction will make it possible to deliver an impactful program of reforms at the European level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;To truly reform the European Union, we intend to create Volt, a progressive pro-European movement, which focuses on delivering real reforms. Volt shall be represented in every member state and in Brussels, to propose and bring forward a coherent program across national governments and in the European Parliament.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We envision at least three strong upsides of this approach:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DRIVE RADICAL REFORMS. Volt is the only solution to deliver real changes in our continent. Envisioning a successful round of elections in selected Member States, such as the Italian general election in 2018, as well as in the European Parliament in 2019, the movement would be able to both propose radical reforms at European level (where reforms are often too conservative) and decrease Member States’ individualistic oppositions to changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MOBILIZE THE ERASMUS GENERATION. As observed during the “Macron” phenomena in France, there is a part of the population –young and not-so-young– that believes in the EU and its mission: the “Erasmus generation”. We believe that Volt has the power to appeal and mobilize this cross-border group and raise its democratic participation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BRING CITIZENS CLOSE TO EUROPE. Volt has the potential to reduce the democratic vacuum currently existing between citizens and European politicians. Applying the above described “American model” – where the same party is represented in national and federal elections – we will create intuitive linkages between national and European politics, and make people participate in a coherent, continental political system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Volt will base each national program on these &lt;a href="https://www.volteuropa.org/challenges"&gt;5 challenges,&lt;/a&gt; soon to be applied in the Italian context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citizens of Europe, join us to save Europe. It is a great opportunity, let’s not waste it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:42:33 +0200</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.voltbelgie.org/a_call_for_europe</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Salvation at your doorstep: why we desperately need Volt</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is not an article aiming at convincing you that the European Union is needed (although it is), that it is one of the most incredible projects we have ever created (although it still is), and that it is something we should hold on to dearly while reforming (although we should). Instead, it is an article explaining how deriving national and regional policies from an overarching set of values and principles would benefit us all, whether at the national, regional, or international level. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Volt was born as a result of a desire to change things: make the European Union a more dynamic, just and influential union, while giving strength to its individual member states. It came from a belief that whether you are German, Romanian or Greek, you’ll be better off by having not only a strong country but a strong Union. As a short summary, Volt is a progressive, pro-European movement based on &lt;a href="http://www.volteuropa.org/vision"&gt;5+1 challenges&lt;/a&gt;. It originates in Italy, but still aims to create other national parties in every European country following the same set of principles. It also has an overarching structure — &lt;a href="http://www.volteuropa.org"&gt;Volt Europa&lt;/a&gt; — following the same guidelines at the regional level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 5+1 challenges are: smart state, economic renaissance, social equality, global balance, citizen empowerment, and  EU reform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason for which it instantly appealed to me was that I am a firm believer in the EU, not only because of its great achievements and potential — such as contributing to peace — but also because, having friends from all over the Union, I believe that we share the same values, ideal and goals. I am French, but maybe more importantly I am European, and I believe that those two are not contradictory but rather reinforce one another. I am proud of my country’s culture, values and history, while still believing that other Europeans share the same underlying, fundamental principles. In short, we share the same hopes and dreams. This is why, when I heard of Volt, I could not have been more excited. Volt's desire to implement its 5 actions in every Member State and in the Union itself is genius: it will bring us closer together and make us stronger, while preserving our diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me finish by saying that the EU admittedly has its downfalls, as do all of our countries. However, I do believe in the saying that “we are stronger together.” Regardless of the usual economic arguments for the EU, I believe that it is grand because we make each other better. We hold each other to higher standards. Just like in any good, happy and healthy relationship, we challenge each other in all possible ways: whether it is by discussing and disagreeing over how to save one of our Member State’s economies, by figuring out how to uphold human rights in our fight against new threats, or by simply trying to move into the 21st century together, while preserving our history and culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As a result, it is now time for us to join forces, dream big like our founders did, change what needs to be changed, and continuously thrive in our development. This is what Volt will do. Volt not only has a vision, it has a plan… a plan for our countries, and a plan for the European Union.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Colombe Cahen-Salvador&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:42:30 +0200</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.voltbelgie.org/salvation_at_your_doorstep_why_we_desperately_need_volt</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The battle for our future</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, March 29, 2017, the UK triggered article 50 of the Treaty of Lisbon, which will mark the beginning of the formal Brexit negotiations. This day will be remembered as the day the UK separated its destiny from the one of Europe, and as the day the European Union lost a fundamental part of its identity. Today is a day of mourning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, March 29, 2017 will not be remembered as the day that doomed the European Project. Indeed, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;today a new hope for Europe is born: Volt&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. A progressive, pro-European movement which focuses on delivering real reforms both at national and supranational levels. Today is also a day of celebration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join the change, today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The status quo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a young Italian, I lived most of my life in a majestic, beautiful, and controversial nation. Despite being home to only 60 million people (0.8% of the world population) and constantly lashed by corruption and political instability, Italy shaped human history and culture disproportionally. For example, in spite of the country’s many flaws –disputable rule of law, inefficient bureaucracy-, the Italian performances in traditional (arts, automotive, food) and unconventional (manufacturing) fields have been outstanding. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a young Italian, I witnessed how our people can overcome any constraint, producing magnificent outcomes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;given mediocre – at best – economic and social conditions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a young European, born just one month before the signing of the Maastricht Treaty, our Union has represented the status quo for all of my life. As most of my peers, I take for granted the benefits derived from the existence of a strong supranational entity, ranging from the most fundamental benefits, such as a prolonged period of peace in the continent or the complete rebuttal of the death penalty, to the minor ones, such as passport-free travelling or the absence of tariffs when shopping for European goods. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a young European, I experienced freedoms that were unthinkable for my grandparents, and that are still unreachable in most regions of the world.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;However, the unique prosperity that my country and Europe have produced for decades might be soon fading away&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Since 2000, Italy has slipped from the 6th to the 12th position in the ranking of world economies. Experts forecast it will be in &lt;a href="https://www.investireoggi.it/economia/declino-economico-italiano-21-esima-potenza-nel-2050-condannati-alla-bassa-crescita/"&gt;21st place&lt;/a&gt; by 2050. Our ageing population entails that in less than 20 years 1/3 of the Italian population will be &lt;a href="http://www.istat.it/it/files/2011/12/futuro-demografico.pdf"&gt;above 65&lt;/a&gt;, and therefore excluded from the labor force. Our public debt is enormous (4th in the world) and constantly growing. In the meanwhile, the European project is failing. As described in this &lt;a href="https://voxmov.eu/2017/03/13/a-call-for-europe/"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, the EU did not manage to cope with any of the major crisis that hit our continent in the last decade. In addition, one of the fastest growing, major economies of the Union is about to leave. Moreover, ever after the Brexit vote, all major European elections are anxiously followed by the world, as there is a fear the any of them could be the one that will destroy the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;My country – as many others in the EU-  is on the path of decline, and the EU’s very existence faces unprecedented threats.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The change&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the face of a crisis, new ideas, new energies, and new perspectives are needed. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;To save the Member States and the European Union, we created Volt, a progressive, pro-European movement&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Volt shall be represented in every Member State and in Brussels, to propose and lead a coherent program of reforms across national governments and in the European institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never before has a political movement planned to expand in each European country, aiming at developing a coherent strategy across the continent.  Never before has a political movement put the concept of the State as a Servant of its citizens at its core. Never before has a political movement been created by young but skilled people that decided to risk everything, to follow their heart and to try to do the right thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:42:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.voltbelgie.org/the_battle_for_our_future</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>European Populists and How to Fight Them</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Macron won the French Presidency, the feeling of relief was overwhelming: the worst potential scenario was avoided. Extremism was defeated, optimism and pro-European views had emerged, and a young, charming, and charismatic leader was elected. This followed the victories of the Netherlands and Austria in defeating far-right populist parties. At first glance, it now looks like the world – or at least Europe – is back on the progressive path, and that the Brexit, Trump’s election, and Turkey’s referendum were simply bumps along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, when taking a step back, partaking in the celebration was difficult for us, not only because of partially diverging political views, but also because of some catastrophic data. Despite the fact that Macron won 66.1% of the votes (20.8 million) – which was way above expectations – Le Pen managed to get an unprecedented number of votes (10.6 million), hereby doubling her father’s results of 2002. Additionally, the level of abstention was the highest it has been since 1969, with 12.1 million people abstaining, and 4.07 million &lt;em&gt;votes blancs &lt;/em&gt;or &lt;em&gt;nuls&lt;/em&gt;. A worrying trend is emerging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes, Macron won by a landslide&lt;/strong&gt;. No, this is not enough; it is disastrous that Le Pen even reached the second round, and even more appalling that she won more than a third of the votes. Although Macron maneuvered successfully to position himself as the only solution in an incredibly polarized political climate, many still felt unrepresented, leading some presidential candidates not to give voting instructions (i.e. Mélenchon).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence, those results should be analyzed as part of a wider scheme: in their last elections, the Netherlands, Austria, and France saw a sustained growth in extremist parties’ support. Additionally, in Italy, despite the general expectation that Renzi (&lt;em&gt;Partito Democratico&lt;/em&gt;) will come out victorious in the next general elections, the populist 5-star movement is polling at over 30%. This raises deep concerns on the future of our countries and our continent. So yes, extremism is being defeated in some European countries, but for how long will this still be the case? The disruptive trends (e.g. globalization, terrorism, and refugee crisis) that led to their surge, are not going away anytime soon. As a result, if the new generation of progressive leaders fails to effectively tackle these challenges, a radically different scenario can be expected in less than a decade. For example, a paralyzed Macron government – in the event of disappointing results in the legislative elections – will boost the&lt;em&gt; Front National&lt;/em&gt;’s performance everywhere in France. In this op-ed, we mentioned only a few European countries, but so many others are moving in similar nationalist directions, just like Hungary and Poland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to realize that it is the duty of our generation to take up responsibility now, and that posting on social media is not enough anymore. Start organizing, thinking and acting to reshape the way political parties work and should work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what Volt wants to do. Volt thinks beyond winning the next elections and wants to restructure the way the political balance currently works in Europe. Volt has a unique selling point, which is that it aims at proposing new ideas, fighting for you, and opposing hatred both at the European level, and in each and every member state. Volt gives a voice to our generation and our beliefs in order to shape a better future for Europe. We need each one of you to join our fight, regardless of your age, background, and experience: you can and should make a difference. We need passion, energy, and willingness to change what needs to be changed. This way, we will evolve from a group to a movement that will be able to overcome the strongest barriers. The future is in our hands; it is time to act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Colombe Cahen-Salvador and Andrea Venzon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:42:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.voltbelgie.org/european_populists_and_how_to_fight_them</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>That 1% moving the world tide – A call to action for all of us</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We live in interesting times, continuously witnessing historical decisions taken by popular vote. A country leaving the EU, an unconventional U.S. president, and a radical constitutional reform in Turkey are only some of the decisions that will influence the path of our societies for decades to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What really strikes me is how – when called to vote on these historical decisions – people are almost equally split, and the final say seems to depend on a small, often minimal margin. Yesterday, the Turkish referendum was approved by 51.4%. The Trump presidency was won due to sometimes only a thousand votes in key states, out of a total of 130 million voters. The plebiscite on the FARC peace agreement in Columbia was rejected by a 0.4% rift. It seems like a tiny majority is shifting the world tide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, this tiny majority – which I refer to as “the 1%” – is pushing the world in a dangerous direction: a world of authoritarian leaders, emotionally and religiously driven policies, and surging military tensions. That 1% seems to be able to steer all of us toward a world of closed borders, closed minds, and closed hearts. However, we are not powerless. I believe that it is time for us – the People who share the conviction that democracy, solidarity, and equality must be upheld no matter what – to act. We cannot delay any further, we cannot hope that someone else will do the job and lead us in the next electoral confrontation. We have to take up responsibility – this is our duty in a democracy. All of us can help steer the world’s tide. We must convince our friends to go out and vote, bringing those poor turnout rates (58% in the US presidential election) to a record high, if necessary. We must engage in conversations with the other side in each matter, to bridge the gaps that are polarizing our society and to try to find a middle ground. We must become the voice of that silent majority that wishes for a better future, instead of hoping that “that guy will not really do what he promised.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you agree, but you don’t know where or how to start: Join Volt. We want to be that Voice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:42:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.voltbelgie.org/that_1_moving_the_world_tide_a_call_to_action_for_all_of_us</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new political party, and a new wave of extremism? </title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Following the incorporation of Volt Deutschland in Hamburg and  a long Sunday night watching the Italian elections until late, I felt two strong contrasting emotions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;On the one hand, the privilege of witnessing the founding of our first national chapter filled me with happiness and pride. Almost 50 Europeans travelled from all over the country to make Volt even more real. Almost 50 Germans - among them students hoping for a better future, professionals that believe that a good job and a good wage are not enough if our society stays flawed, pensioners that are worried for their grandchildren - went through hours of passionate discussions, note-taking, exciting decisions and to finally stand as one. Almost 50 citizens decided to stand up, and not give in to a gloomy future.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;On the other hand, the excitement for this great achievement for our movement was soon paired with  a feeling of anger, when the first projections of the Italian elections came in. After witnessing extremists achieving historical heights in France, gaining 90 seats in the German parliament, and joining the governing coalition in Austria, the electoral earthquake in Italian peninsula ringed a bell inside me; the same bell that ringed the day of Brexit, when I decided to create this movement. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;When the soon-to-be 3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;rd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt; largest economy of the EU will be ruled by a far-right party, and/or an anti-vaccines movement, we have to act. When in almost every constituency of one of the biggest disadvantaged areas of Europe – the south of Italy – the same anti-vaccines party is chosen by more than 50% of the population, something is happening. When the future Prime Minister of this same country will be either one that has so far refused every public debate with other political leaders, or one that would “drop every refugee back on the African shores with a bag of peanuts,” we have to stand up and oppose this.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;In Volt, many of us feel divided between the excitement of being part of something great, innovative, and hopeful, and the fear of not being fast enough, and being too late to steer the tide of this continent. That’s why I am writing this; to share a few concrete actions that we need to act upon to make sure that our excitement brings about change, that our fears are channeled into the motivation needed to achieve our vision, and that our movement changes European political landscape, for good.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Europe is a great mean, not an end in itself: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Our aims are to increase the effectiveness of our public administrations, bring sustainable growth and economic opportunities, curb inequalities, fight for a better future , give everyone a voice, ensure peace and cooperation within this continent &amp;amp; beyond, and so much more. To achieve this, we have to reform the EU and strengthen it. However, we shall not fall into the mistake of loving Europe for the sake of loving it; blind patriotism - both at European and national level – has hardly ever brought any good. We love Europe because of the great benefit that has brought on our lives, and we will fight to improve it until its impact will be even greater, and will be more evenly shared with those Europeans that did not feel it yet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We do politics, at every level: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;I want to be clear: Volt is more than a European movement. We define ourselves as pan-European because we aim not only to be in every European country, but in every layer of government. We believe this is the only way to truly have a political weight, impact the lives of people, and bring solutions to local and continental problems. I heard a few times the proposal of only campaigning on European topics at European level. If we were to follow this model, we would not only gather a very limited amount of political support (and hence not bring any change), but we would also be incredibly elitarian: when you can hardly pay your bills, your child does not have access to a decent education, or you have to travel to another country to have a surgery, a European army is probable the last of your problems. Each one of us should always remember that if we want to change this continent, we cannot forget about the needs of a huge share of its citizens.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The time to be shy is gone, now is the time to act: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;6 months ago, I was glad that Volt could attract many “silent” members – people that liked our movement, maybe helped a bit, but would not publicly stand for what we stand for, for our name, for our vision. We were a small movement, with an identity still to be shaped, and a lot to show. Today, after hundreds of meetings, an incredible diversity, 22 country teams, and our key political positioning online, it is not the time to be shy anymore. Today, I ask each one of us who decided to fill that online form to take up responsibility and make Volt more than a like on Facebook. Are you in a political party? Consider leaving it. Do you have a wide network of friends? Involve them. Did you always have an idea to improve the status quo? Propose it. In 6 months, each one of you reading this email will be a leader, each one of you will embody our values, and each one of you will be an active part of a political revolution, or Volt will have failed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;The choice is yours. #ReVolt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:42:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.voltbelgie.org/a_new_political_party_and_a_new_wave_of_extremism</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To all Europeans. To all who are Bold &amp; Brave. To all the Innovators.</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Volt was started by a group of passionate people who want to change the status quo for the better. We have no big endorsements, no famous names, and no gigantic donations. We are not politicians and we are not running to secure a good pension. We are young and daring Europeans who have seen our continent decaying and who will not wait until it is too late to take up responsibility. We are not supposed to be in politics; we were not expected, but we are right here. Join us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stand for a strong and integrated Europe, because we know that – despite its flaws – the EU has massively and positively affected our lives already and can continue to do so! We will oppose anyone who wants to take these achievements away from us. There are not only the fundamental and often mentioned benefits (such as 70 years of peace, many periods of economic prosperity, and a steady spread of human and civil rights), but also daily and unmissable advantages, such as lower prices of goods coming from within the EU, the birth of low-costs airlines, and the clampdown on roaming costs. Don’t get us wrong: We know that the EU in its current form is not really working, and that it is stuck in anachronistic national clashes and its inability to act. That is why we pledge to reform and advance the EU, with all our energy. Join us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stand for the basic values that ensure human decency, and that in our advanced societies should not even need to be debated anymore. The right to marry whomever you love, the right to find a safe harbor when war is raging around you and your family, the right to find a job, the right to receive the same wage regardless of who you are, and the right to partake in society independent of your age or physical and mental abilities. We are not saying what we are supposed to say, we are standing for those unalienable human rights that reactionary politicians are not willing to uphold anymore. We will not compromise on these fundamental values, and we will achieve these results. Join us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are the newcomers, the innovators, the pioneers. Volt will truly digitalize the government, cut inefficiencies, achieve full transparency and completely clampdown on corruption, because this is our way of thinking, of living, and of being. None of us can understand why we use paper-based application to interact with our public administration officials, or why it is so hard to track public spending when technology could solve all of these problems in the span of an administration. Political will for real change seems to be scarce – we have tons of it! Join us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are for a strong and integrated European Union, if you believe in human rights and social equality, and if you are for innovation within our administration and our economies, join us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are currently building the first pan-European, progressive political movement. We need team members, experts, supporters, and followers: from wherever you are, whichever experience you gathered, and with the little time you have, you can contribute and build Volt with us. We mainly work online, and we gather anywhere where enough Volters are available – if you want to test yourself and fight for your beliefs and values, this is the moment. If you just like the idea, support us on our social media, share our posts, spread the word.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:42:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.voltbelgie.org/to_all_europeans_to_all_who_are_bold_brave_to_all_the_innovators</link>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
